---NewMov字幕翻譯小組制作---
翻譯&校對﹕bigliar
(. ''If I Had $ 1 000000''
by Barenaked Ladies))
--------------------------
本字幕所有權益歸制作人所有
純屬翻譯愛好者交流學習使用
謝絕它用，否則一切后果自負
--------------------------
英文片名﹕My Boss's Daughter
中文片名﹕----老板的女儿----
有句老話，你們都曾听人說過﹕
You know, you ever heard
someone say that old expression,
“凡事皆有因”，
不過，我覺得這句話用在我身上并不恰當
''Everything happens for a reason''?
Well, I don't think that applies to me.
我是說，我把每個早上都花在
匆匆忙忙赶去上班上面了
I mean, I spend every morning
rushing to work
奮力地赶著同一班地鐵，
做著同一份無謂的差事
trying to catch the same subway
to the same lousy job.
有什么理由會這樣﹖
What's the reason for that?
我在芝加哥最大的出版社任一名調查員
See, I'm a researcher for one of the
biggest publishing houses in Chicago,
但是我真正想呆的部門是在創意部
but where I really belong is in Creative.
問題是，我的老板還沒意識到這點，
所以我算是失意至极了
The problem is, is my boss doesn't
know it yet, so I'm totally frustrated.
我的朋友保羅一直跟我說
While my friend Paul keeps telling me,
“你要樂觀一點，要積极一點”
''You gotta be optimistic.
You gotta be positive. ''
行，行，你們知道嗎﹖
OK. OK. You know what?
今天會是我的幸運日，今天會是我的...
Today is gonna be my lucky day.
Today is gonna be my...
- 啊﹗
- 噢﹗哇哦﹗
- Aah!
- Oh! Wow!
- 嘿，看這個，今天是你的幸運日
- 你看到了嗎﹖
- Hey, look at that, lt's your lucky day,
- Did you just see that?
噢，這种事我都見過無數次了
Oh, l've seen it a million times,
- 你要不要﹖
- 不要
- You want it?
- No,
我也不要，給你吧，這下你有新的公文包了
l don't want it, Go ahead,
You got a new briefcase,
是啊，說不定上面有名字或者什么
Yeah, maybe its got a name
on it or something,
- 噢，拜托，你怎么回事﹖你是傻瓜嗎﹖
- 什么﹖
- Oh, come,,, What are you, nuts?
- What?
- 你要把它還回去﹖
- 是的
- You're gonna return it?
- Yeah,
你不是剛說過你需要一個新包嗎﹖
Did you not just say
you needed a new one?
是的，等我升職的時候
Yeah, when l get my raise,
你在那干了不是有...一年了嗎﹖
Haven't you been working
there for, like, a year?
我敢打賭泰勒甚至都不知道你在他那干，
換作是我，我會為此非常生气
l bet Taylor doesn't even know
you work there, l'd be pissed,
- 你生气嗎﹖我會生气
- 是的，我...我有一點生气
- Are you pissed? l'd be pissed,
- Yeah, l'm-l'm a little pissed,
這一說倒讓我想到一件事，
我從來沒有真正見過你發火
You know, come to think of it,
l've never really seen you angry before,
漢德森，你曾見過湯姆真正發一回火嗎﹖
Henderson, you ever
seen Tom really angry?
- 沒有
- 好了，沒錯，我沒有發過火
- No,
- All right, fine, So l don't get angry,
怎么了，是件坏事﹖
What is that, a bad thing?
你要知道，如果你把怒气一直壓抑著，
那么遲早有一天...
lt's, you know, you keep it bottled up
and then sooner or later,
...你來上班的時候，你會干掉所有人，
用一支...
you come into work and you mow
everyone down with one of those,,,
- AK-47自動步槍
- AK-47，僅僅是為了給某人
留個印象，比如...
- AK-47,
- AK-47, You know, just to impress, uh,,,
- 茱迪.福斯特
- Jodie Foster,
好吧，我會等你們休假
的時候再動手，行了嗎﹖
(chuckles)) All right, l'll do it
on your day off, all right?
哦，來了，你的“茱迪.福斯特”來了
(Paul) Touch? There she is,
lt's your Jodie Foster,
保羅，別這樣，老兄
Paul, come on, man,
如果你只是坐在這，你怎么可能認識她﹖
How you ever gonna get
to know her if you just sit there?
她是泰勒的女儿，老兄，我不可能就...
lt's Taylor's daughter, man, l can't just,,,
你不可能就什么﹖嗯﹖
你想一輩子沒出息嗎﹖嗯﹖
You can't just what? Huh? Are you
gonna be a loser your whole life? Hmm?
勇敢地走過去，跟她說話，上呀
Just go over there
and talk to her, Go, Go,
- 行行行，我上，我上
- 你上
- OK, fine, l'm going, l'm going,
- You're going,
打扰了...
Excuse me,
啊﹗
Aah!
(baby crying))
(mouthing))
嗨，我是...
Hi, l'm--
啊
Ah,,,
我...噢﹗
l-
- Oh!
哦...我...他...
Uh,,, l-
- He wa--
噢
Oh,
(dog growling))
噢﹗噢...
Oh! Uh,,,
- 你把我的狗怎么了﹖
- 夫人...
- What are you doing to my dog?
- Ma'am,,,
- 誰在逗我的狗﹖
- 沒人逗你的狗，它...
- Who's taunting my dog?
- No one's taunting your dog, He--
噢﹗哦...
Oh! Uh,,,
哦，這...這只狗...嗯...
Um, the-the d-
- Um,,,
不如你坐我的位置﹖坐吧
Here, why don't you take my seat? Here,
不賴，你真不賴
Great, Now, that's great,
多給我兩分鐘，我都能比你更接近她
Two more minutes, and l'm gonna
be closer than you are,
看，有机會了，快過去
Look, Opening, Go,
快過去
Just go,
快上
Go, Go,
沒事，快過去
lt's OK, Go, just go,
“萊克街，下一站是萊克街”
(conductor) Lake Street.
Lake Street is next.
你是湯姆.斯坦菲爾德，是嗎﹖調查部的﹖
You're Tom Stansfield, right?
From Research?
沒錯，沒錯，湯姆，湯姆.斯坦菲爾德
Yeah, Yeah, Tom,
Tom Stansfield,
調查部的...斯坦菲爾德
Stansfield from Research,
那是一項很有前途的運動，知道嗎﹖
lt's a growing sport, you know?
保羅，她不可能認為那是一本摔跤雜志
Paul, there is no way that she thought
that it was a wrestling magazine,
噢，拜托，忘了這件事吧，行不行﹖
Oh, come on, Get over it, OK?
你是有點尷尬，不過已經發生了，行了嗎﹖
You're a little embarrassed,
lt happens, OK?
我跟你說，從包里掉出一本裸男雜志...
Let me tell you something,
lf l had a dime for every time
...對我來說是家常便飯了，
開玩笑，開玩笑
a gay naked magazine fell out of my,,,
l'm kidding, l'm kidding,
什么﹖保羅﹗
What? Paul!
不說了，不過認真說來你是出了點丑
No, But seriously,
so you're a little humiliated,
但至少現在我們确定她知道你是誰了，對不對﹖
At least now we've established
that she knows who you are, right?
- 我要被赶出這家公司了
- 不，你不會的
- l'm gonna have to leave the company,
- No, you're not,
噢，天吶，是她
Oh, God, There she is,
哦，還有，我需要馬上看到泰國方面的校樣
Oh, and l need to see the proofs
on Thailand immediately,
就這樣，還有別的什么沒有﹖
All right, What else have we got?
- 你是湯姆﹖
- 是的
- Are you Tom?
- Yes,
- 泰勒先生要見你
- 噢...好的
- Mr, Taylor wants to see you,
- Oh,,, OK,
好的
OK,
看到沒有﹖你的机會來了，這就是命運，
這就是我一直在說的...
OK, you see? This is your chance, This
is fate, This is what l'm talking about,
...去創意部發展的一個嶄新的机會，
你就是做這份工作的最佳人選
lt's about that new opening in Creative
and you're the man for the job,
你將要走進去，你將要向他推銷那些書的构思
You're gonna go in there and you're
gonna pitch him those book ideas,
不行，只是我...我真的還沒准備好
No, l just,,, l'm really not ready,
好了，廢話少說，現在我們要飛黃騰達了
Let's get to business,
Now we're steppin' up, OK,
來吧，你將要走進去，你將要給他狠狠一擊
Come on, You're gonna go in there,
you're gonna pitch him an inside curve,,,
等等，我的蘭色文件夾呢﹖
Wait, wait, Where is my blue folder?
你不需要它，別再找借口了，來吧
You don't need it, Enough with
the excuses already, Come here,
- 你看上去很棒，你感覺很棒嗎﹖
- 我覺得想吐
- You look good, You feel good?
- l feel like l'm gonna throw up,
很好，就是需要這种感覺
Well, that's good,
l want you to use that, OK?
這是什么﹖你老爸的﹖
不錯，快進去吧，好嗎﹖
What is this? This dad's?
lt's nice, Now get in there, OK?
- 別...別碰我屁股
- 什么﹖只是輕輕一拍，很輕的
- Don't-don't touch my ass,
- What? lt was a light spank, lt was light,
- 嘿
- Hey,
- 嗯，我就這么進去﹖
- 噢，別急，他還沒結束
- Uh, do l just go in there?
- Um, no, He's not finished yet,
- 你可以先在那邊坐一會
- 噢，好的
- but you can have a seat over there,
- Oh, OK,
我來解釋給你听，漢德森
Let me explain something
to you, Henderson,
我不是不喜歡你的构思，
我根本就是認為它們令人厭惡
l did not dislike your ideas,
l found them loathsome,
我憎厭它們
l hated them,
- 你可以走人了
- 离開你的辦公室﹖
- You're dismissed,
- From your office?
你想得美﹗
Nice try,
- 祝你好運，你會需要它的
- 他可以見你了
- Good luck, You're gonna need it,,,
- He's ready to see you,
你可以進去了
You can come in,
你們知道嗎﹖獨立戰爭后我們根本不應該放松﹗
You know what? We should have
never let up after the Revolution!
坐下，坐吧，要咖啡嗎﹖
Sit down, Sit down, Coffee?
我們不該把你留在懸崖上，
我們應該把你推進海里
We shouldn't have left you at toehold,
We should have driven you to the sea!
我听說你威脅要用AK-47掃射這個地方...
Now,,, what's this l hear
about you making threats
...是怎么回事﹖
to spray this place with an AK-47?
什么﹖
What?
噢，噢，噢，不是的，那個...
我只是開個玩笑
Oh, oh, oh, No, That,,,
l was just making a joke,
哦，你認為很有趣﹖殺死這里的所有人﹖
Oh, that's funny to you?
Killing everyone in this office?
不，不不不，是...
保羅說我從未發過火...
No, No, No, no, no, no, The,,,
Paul said how l never get angry,,,
那么你嘲笑侏儒的事又怎么講﹖
And what about you
making fun of midgets?
我從未嘲笑過侏儒
l never made fun of midgets,
你說跟一個侏儒約會會很有趣
You said it'd be fun to date one
因為那樣你就可以把啤酒擱在她的頭上
because then you could rest
your beer on her head,
不，不，我從來沒有說過這种話
No, No, l never said anything like that,
很顯然漢德森認為你說了
Apparently Henderson thinks you did,
我一向很有幽默感，不過你這种笑話
不但不好笑而且很不健康
Now l've got a good sense of humor,
but that's just plain sick,
- 但是，先生，我沒有說過...
- 奧德莉﹖
- But, sir, l didn't say,,,
- Audrey?
- 我叫你拿哪份文件﹖
- 嗯，普拉特那份﹖
- Which file did l ask you for?
- Uh, the Platt file?
- 約翰.普拉特，不是山姆.普拉特
- 對不起，是我沒有想...
- John Platt, Not Sam Platt,
- l'm sorry, l guess l didn't think that,,,
沒錯，你不用腦子想
That's right, You didn't think,
現在，要是不太麻煩你的話，
能不能把正确的那份文件拿給我﹖
Now if it's not too much trouble,
if you could fetch me the right file,,,
- 好的
- 順便給我和湯姆拿些炸圈餅
- OK,
- And get Tom and me some doughnuts,
好的
OK,
听說你一直想見我...
Now,,, l'm told you've been trying
to schedule a meeting with me
...想談談你的构思，是什么构思﹖
about some ideas,
What are they?
噢，嗯...是的，我是...是有一些构思
Oh, uh,,, yeah, l had-l had some ideas,
- 咖啡有問題﹖
- 噢，沒有，很好喝
- Something wrong with the coffee?
- Uh, no, lt's fine,
- 那你為何作出這么一副表情﹖
- 什么﹖
- Why'd you make a face?
- What?
噢，這個...咖啡有一點苦，不過...
Oh, well,,, lt's-it's a little bitter, but,,,
- 見鬼，奧德莉，給我進來﹗
- 先生，真的，沒...沒什么大不了的
- Jesus, Audrey, get in here!
- Sir, really, it's f,,, lt's not a problem,
- 我打的嗝味道都比這個好
- 先生，沒關系的
- l've burped up stuff better than this,
- Sir, it's fine,
- 有什么問題嗎﹖
- 你嘗嘗湯姆的咖啡
- ls something wrong?
- Taste Tom's coffee,
不用了，真的，沒關系
No, really, lt's OK,
- 你認為如何﹖
- 嗯，是不太好喝
- How would you rate that?
- Well, it's not that great,
不太好喝﹖我想是不太好喝，
湯姆覺得根本就難以下咽
Not that great? l guess so,
Tom thinks it's shit,
奧德莉，你是不是弱智﹖
Audrey, are you retarded?
我不是反問你。你是弱智嗎﹖
lt's not a rhetorical question,
Are you retarded?
不，我不是弱智
No, l'm not retarded,
因為一個弱智的人都能泡咖啡，
我說得對嗎﹖湯姆﹖
Because a retarded person can make
a cup of coffee, Am l right, Tom?
噢，我...我不太...真的不太清楚
Oh, l,,, l don't-l don't really know much
對于殘障人士的缺陷
about the limitations
of the handicapped,
我知道有一家職業介紹所，可以推荐殘障人士
來工作，薪水是每小時4美元
l know of an employment agency that
hires out retarded people for $4 an hour,
所以，如果泡杯咖啡對你來說都太難了的話，
班尼特小姐...
So, if making a cup of coffee is too
difficult a task for you, Miss Bennett,
或許你該告訴我一聲，我好聯系那家職介所...
perhaps you'd be good enough to let
me know, and l'll contact this agency
...找一名殘障人士來做這份工作
and give a retarded person a job,
哇
(mouths)) Wow,
- 我剛才對她不會太嚴厲吧，嗯﹖
- 嗯，她的确不夠老練
- l wasn't too rough on her, was l?
- Well, she is new and all,
或許我是太過分了，但是你知不知道
我所面臨的是什么樣的問題﹖
Maybe l was out of line, But do you
understand what l'm dealing with?
我是說，我正要找人填補創意部的一個空缺職位
l mean, here l am trying
to fill a position in Creative,
可是我好像找不到一個足夠
可靠的人來獲取我的信任
and l can't seem to find one person
responsible enough to earn my trust,
有時候我甚至不知道這里到底
有沒有人知道自己在做什么
l sometimes wonder if anyone here
even knows what they're doing,
我能夠理解你為什么會有這种看法，
先生，不過...
l can understand how you
could see it that way, sir, but,,,
所以你認為我剛才并不過分﹖
So you don't think
l was out of line?
嗯，如果你要說的是，一個公司...
Well, if what you're saying
is that a company
...的強大程度受制于公司內部最薄弱的環節，
這是有道理的，不過...
is only as strong as its weakest link,
that makes sense, but,,,
太對了，完全正确
Exactly, That's exactly right,
一個公司的強大程度受制于
公司內部最薄弱的環節
A company is only as strong
as its weakest link,
- 是...
- 奧德莉，進來﹗
- Yeah,,,
- Audrey, get in here!
你說得對，湯姆，我對她太溫柔了
You were right, Tom,
l was too soft on her,
- 什么﹖不是
- 什么事﹖
- What? No,
- Yeah?
奧德莉，在跟湯姆詳細商討之后...
Audrey, after talking it over
with Tom here,
我認識到我必須要讓你离開了
l've come to realize that
l'm gonna have to let you go,
- 你要解雇我﹖﹗
- 抱歉，只能這樣子了
- You're firing me?!
- l'm sorry, lt's just not working out,
- 但是，先生，我剛才是建議...
- 我對工作盡心盡責
- But, sir, l was suggesting,,,
- l take my job very seriously,
一根鏈條的牢固程度受制于它的最薄弱的環節
A chain is only as strong
as its weakest link,
- 沒錯，但問題還有完全不同的另一面
- 謝謝你在一旁加油添醋
- Right, but there's a whole other side,
- Thanks for the support,
奧德莉，今天下班之前清空你的辦公桌
Audrey, empty out your desk
by the end of the day,
- 好
- 先生，這...我...
- Fine,
- Sir, this,,, l,,,
多謝你幫我理清這個問題，湯姆
Thanks for straightening me
out there, Tom,
是的，是的，但是我剛才沒有
表達出我真正想說的東西
Right, right, But l didn't get to say
what l wanted to say,
噢，你的构思，當然了，
找我的新秘書給你安排一次會面吧
Oh, your ideas, of course, Schedule
an appointment with my new secretary,
湯姆，你還好嗎﹖
Tom, Are you OK?
嗯...是，當然
Uh,,, yeah, sure,
看到你的樣子，我猜他今天早上又對某個人...
l'm guessing by the way
you look he's on another one
...暴跳如雷了吧
of his rampages this morning,
- 絕對是
- 真是的
- Definitely,
- Damn,
我原本還希望能碰上他情緒好的時候
l was hoping to catch him
in a good mood,
這個，嗯...很可能不會有這种時候了
Yeah, that's, um,,,
that's probably not gonna happen,
我今晚要去參加一個派對，
可是我老爸要我留在家里...
l'm supposed to go to this party tonight,
but my dad's making me housesit
...照看他那只蠢鳥，
就因為他自己這個周末要出去
for his stupid bird while
he's away this weekend,
為何你不進去告訴他你不想留在家里﹖
Well, why don't you go in there
and tell him you're not gonna do it?
我不能就這么...
l can't just,,,
你不能就什么﹖我的意思是，為何不過你
自己要過的生活，享受一個自在的周末﹖
You can't just what? l mean, live your
own life and have a free weekend?
不，不是那么回事
No, it's not that,
- 沒錯，就是這么回事
- 對了
- Wait, it is that,
- Yeah,
- 我就應該去參加派對
- 對了，當然該這樣
- l should just go to that party,
- Yeah, of course,
嗯...好了，我要回去...工作了
Well, um,,, OK, l'm gonna
go back to, uh, work,
好的
OK, sure,
湯姆﹖我知道這可能有點唐突
Tom? l know this might seem
a little out of place
因為我們還只是剛剛認識
because we barely
even know each other,
不過，你今晚有什么安排嗎﹖
But, do you have any plans tonight?
沒有，沒，沒
(mouths)) No, no, no,
- 嗯...沒有，我...我有空得很
- 我們不會太晚回家的
- Uh,,, no, l'm-l'm wide open,
- We won't be home too late,
嘿，沒關系
Hey, it's no problem,
派對7點鐘開始，你能6點來我老爸家嗎﹖
So the party starts at 7,
You could be at my dad's house by 6?
- 沒問題
- 你确定你沒問題﹖
- Sure,
- You sure you're cool with this?
- 你開我玩笑﹖
- 湯姆，你真是太可愛了
- Are you kidding me?
- Tom, you're such a sweetheart,
太謝謝你了，我真是愛死你了
Thank you so much,
l'm gonna love you forever for this,
- 哈哈，我厲害吧﹖
- 你看﹖我怎么教你的﹖
- All right, Yeah, who's the man now?
- See? What'd l tell you?
(chuckles)) l'm a lady-killer,
我是個情圣
他怎么會對照看房子這么激動﹖
How the hell could he be
so excited about housesitting?
他人好，爸爸，就這么簡單，
絕大多數男孩根本不會愿意做這种事
He's nice, Daddy, That's how,
Most guys wouldn't even offer to do that,
我不太确定我要不要讓他照看我的鳥
l don't know if l want him
around my bird,
噢，爸爸，你放松點行不行﹖
沒事的，我保証，行了嗎﹖
Oh, Dad, will you just relax?
lt's gonna be fine, l promise, OK?
我一到那邊就打電話回來查問，8點鐘的時候
l'll check in as soon
as l get there, 8:00,
如果我覺得有什么不對勁，
你就得回家里來
lf l sense anything's wrong,
you're coming back here,
行了，行了
OK, OK,
(. light rock)
很好，很准時
Very good, Right on time,
噢，先生，嗯...嘿，那個是熊夾子嗎﹖
Oh, sir, Uh,,,
Hey, is that a bear trap?
是的，防止鄰居家的小孩進入我的院子
Yes, lt's to keep the neighbor's kids
out of my yard,
先生，我只想告訴你，我有多么感謝你
Sir, l just wanted to let you know
how much l appreciate you,,,
嗯...今晚的這一切
well,,, letting tonight happen,
我知道今晚的派對對麗莎很重要，
我認為你做得很正确
l mean, l know it means a lot to Lisa,
and l think you're doing the right thing,
我不知道你有什么圖謀，斯坦菲爾德
l don't know what
you're planning, Stansfield,
但你的態度弄得我很緊張
but you're attitude
is making me very nervous,
- 襪子是干淨的，是嗎﹖
- 嗯...
- Those socks are clean, right?
- Um,,,
- 你猶豫了，穿上鞋套
- 你說真的﹖
- You hesitated, Put those on,
- Are you serious?
如果要看電視，遙控器在這
lf you want to watch TV,
the remote's there,
那個面板控制燈、警報、天窗，等等
That panel controls the lights,
alarm, skylight, etc,
知道了，或許我一個都用不上
Yeah, l probably won't
use any of that stuff,
- 你知道的，派對是7點鐘開始
- 派對﹖
- You know, since the party starts at 7,
- Party?
我跟麗莎說得很清楚，
你在這里不能有任何客人
l made it clear to Lisa you're not
to have any guests in here,
你是唯一被允許呆在這所房子里的人
You're the only one
allowed in the house,
- 什么﹖麗莎不在這﹖
- 不在，當然不在
- What? Lisa's not here?
- No, Of course not,
麗莎去參加派對...
Lisa's at the party,,,
而我留在這里
and l'm staying here,
這一點對你而言這么難以理解﹖斯坦菲爾德﹖
ls this concept too complicated
for you, Stansfield?
別碰家具
Don't touch the furniture,
這是我的鳥的房間
And this is my bird's room,
他有自己的房間﹖
(chuckles)) He's got his own room?
很酷
That's cool,
我的小寶貝怎么樣﹖
- (gasps))
- How's my little boy?
- 他叫OJ
- OJ﹖跟那個殺人犯的名字一樣﹖
- This is OJ,
- OJ? Like the murderer?
不，是跟那個橄欖球手的名字一樣，OJ.辛普森
No, Like the football player,
OJ Simpson,
我已經調好鬧鐘，
你一听到它響起，就給他喂食
l've set the alarm,
When you hear it go off, feed him,
哇，給這些小家伙喂食什么﹖
- (mice squeaking))
- Aw, What do l feed these little guys?
它們不用喂食，它們是食物，
他的食譜很丰富，不過它們是他最愛的食物
They don't get fed, They are the food,
His diet varies, but they're his favorites,
嘿，這些門你都不用關﹖
Hey, don't you have to shut these doors?
不再需要了，自從他的配偶死后，
他就一直很消沉
Not anymore, He's been depressed
since his mate died,
他不飛了，只是坐在他的籠子里
He won't fly, Just sits in his cage,
藥，10點鐘給他吃兩顆
Medication, Give him two
of these at 1 0:00,
我必須把這些塞進他的喉嚨﹖
l have to shove these down his throat?
只要塞一顆，另一顆塞入他的直腸
Just one, The other is inserted
into his rectum,
別擔心，這不會讓他太難受的
Don't worry, lt's not
too unpleasant for him,
- 他不咬人吧，會不會﹖
- 不會，除非你逗他
- He doesn't bite, does he?
- No, Not unless you taunt him,
你沒打算逗他吧，嗯﹖湯姆﹖
You're not planning on taunting him,
are you, Tom?
- 沒有
- 我認為，那种行為真的很病態
- No,
- l mean, that'd be really sick,
沒有，當然沒有
No, of course not,
還有最重要的一點，務必要給他喝夠一品脫的水
And the most important thing,
make sure he gets a pint of water,
藥物會使他脫水，他就會呼吸困難
The medication tends to dry him out
and then he can't breathe,
- 好的
- 好了，我該走了
- OK,
- Well, l must be off,
- 漢德森應該還等在外面
- 漢德森﹖我以為你解雇他了
- Henderson should be waiting outside,
- Henderson? l thought you fired him,
因為他的构思很愚蠢﹖當然不會
Because his ideas were stupid?
Of course not,
他要開車送我去火車站
He's gonna drive me to the train station,
等麗莎和漢斯一回來你就可以走了
So, you can leave as soon
as Lisa and Hans get back,
- 漢斯﹖
- 麗莎的男朋友
- Hans?
- Lisa's boyfriend,
記住，嗯...碗里的水、藥，還有...
So remember, uh,,, water in the bowl,
medication, and,,,
我不在的時候這間房子發生任何事，我唯你是問
anything happens to this house
while l'm gone, l'll kill you,
(door shuts))
你在照看房子﹖你開我玩笑吧
(Paul over phone)) You're housesitting?
You gotta be kidding me.
我知道，真是見鬼了
(Tom)) l know, it sucks,
你在說什么呀﹖你不懂嗎﹖這是一次考驗
What are you talking about?
Don't you see? This is a test.
你照看好泰勒的房子，又提出了不少好构思
You watch Taylor's house,
come up with a couple of great ideas
如果一切都順利，你就能升職了
and if everything goes smooth,
you get the promotion.
- 你這樣認為﹖
- 當然了，還有更容易的方法嗎﹖
- You think so?
- Of course I do. What could be easier?
(crackles))
(. ''Not What I Wanted'' by Evan Olson))
你干什么呀，漢斯﹖快過來
(Lisa giggling)) What are you
doing, Hans? Come here.
寶貝，如果你不立刻讓我給你
擦上這個，你會晒傷的
Baby, you're gonna burn so bad if you
don't let me put this on you right now.
噢，天吶，你嚇到我了，漢斯，
你是個神經病，快放下來
Oh, my God. You scared me, Hans.
You're insane. Put that down.
想給我擦嗎﹖幫我擦點防晒劑
Want to put some on me?
Put some lotion on me.
- 杰克在嗎﹖
- 嘿...什么﹖你是誰﹖
- ls Jack around?
- Hey,,, what? Who are you?
別緊張，我是萊德.泰勒，
杰克的儿子，我從后門進來的
lt's OK, l'm Red Taylor, l'm Jack's son,
l let myself in the back,
- 噢，嘿，我是湯姆.斯坦菲爾德
- 嘿
- Oh, Hey, Tom Stansfield,
- Hey,
湯姆，幸會，我打攪你了嗎﹖
Tom, nice to meet you,
Am l interrupting something here?
噢，不，嗯...我剛...嗯...噢，你的鞋
Oh, no, Uh,,, l was,,, uh,,,
Oh, your shoes,
是耐克鞋，嗯，听著，湯姆，
你能幫我個忙嗎﹖我的電視指南不見了
Nike, Uh, listen, Tom, can you
do me a favor? l lost my TV Guide.
我過來看看我老爸這會不會還有一份
l came over here to see if maybe
my dad's got a copy of one,
你沒看到哪里有電視指南嗎﹖有沒有﹖
You haven't seen a copy of
the guide laying around, have you?
- 我妹妹在嗎﹖
- 不在，她出去參加派對了
- My sister in?
- No, actually she's out for the evening,
- 找到了
- 噢
- Bingo, (chuckles))
- Oh,
那么，嗯，你來這里是...
So, uh, you're here to,,,
- 照看房子
- 噢
- Housesit,
- Oh,
對了，或許最好別告訴麗莎我順道來過這里
Yeah, it's probably for the best if you
don't, uh, tell Lisa that l stopped by,
- 為什么﹖有什么問題嗎﹖
- 你知道她有多保守啦
- Why? ls there a problem?
- Well, you know how uptight she is,
- 是嗎﹖
- 我是這個家里比較不受傳統約束的人
- Really?
- l'm more the free spirit of the family,
噢，噢，老兄，看到這個了嗎﹖
Oh, Oh, boy, See that right there?
- 克絲蒂.艾莉﹖
- 是的，我和她的女仆約會過
- Kirstie Alley?
- Yeah, l dated her maid,
- 真的﹖
- 我剝光了克絲蒂.艾莉的女仆
- Really?
- l boned Kirstie Alley's maid,
而且是在他們拍攝《看誰在說話》期間
（《看誰在說話》由約翰.屈伏塔/
布魯斯.威利斯/克絲蒂.艾莉主演）
And this is while they were
making Look Who's Talking ,
哇哦，真了不起
Wow, that's really something,
我再跟你說件事，你知道米歇爾.菲佛嗎﹖
l'll tell you another thing,
You know Michelle Pfeiffer?
知道
Yeah,
我干過米歇爾.菲佛的表妹
l did the deed
with Michelle Pfeiffer's cousin,
- 哇哦
- 就在那外面的矮樹叢中
- Wow,
- Right out there in those bushes,
- 厲害
- 啊，她長得就跟米歇爾一模一樣
- Right,
- Ah, she looked just like Michelle, too,
除了她是黑發而不是金發
except she was brunette
instead of blond,
還有她比較矮比較胖
and she was kinda short and dumpy,
噢，你真是有著多姿多彩的生活，萊德
Well, uh, ya certainly have
an interesting life, Fred,
你結婚了嗎﹖湯姆﹖
You married, Tom?
- 沒有，我還是單身
- 沒有女朋友﹖
- No, l'm single,
- No girlfriend?
沒有，不是，實際上我有過女朋友，
不過，嗯，我們分手了
No, and, no, actually l had a girlfriend,
but we, uh, broke up,
- 啊
- Ah,
听著，我真的要工作了，
既然你找到了電視指南...
Listen, l really gotta get back to work,
and since you got your TV Guide and,,,
那么你們分手了﹖太糟糕了
So, you broke up, huh?
That's too bad,
- 你的前女友漂亮嗎﹖
- 是的
- Was your ex a looker?
- Yeah,
是的，在我看來她挺漂亮的
Yeah, in my opinion she was,
我敢打賭你的皮夾里還留著她的照片
l bet you you still keep a picture
of her in your wallet,
- 是啊，我是留著
- 能看看嗎﹖
- Yeah, l do,
- Can l see it?
- 好吧，我想可以
- 太好了
- Yeah, l suppose,
- OK,
讓我在皮夾里找一找，這就是她
Let me find her
in here, There she is,
噢﹗湯姆，你真是個幸運的家伙﹗
(laughing)) Oh!
Tom, you lucky man!
- 是啊
- 噢，她的屁股真是迷人﹗
- Yeah,
- Oh, she is a real piece of ass!
噢，我可以干她的后花園干一整天﹗
Oh, l could knock on that back door
all day long!
- 是嗎﹖她...她是個漂亮的女孩
- 哇哦
- Yeah? Sh-she's a pretty girl,
- Wow,
她的床上功夫一定很行﹗
告訴我她的床上功夫很行吧，湯姆
She has gotta be wicked in bed,
Tell me she's wicked in bed, Tom,
我敢打賭每天夜里她都干得你的
小弟弟皮開肉綻
l bet you she banged your johnson raw
every single night,
- 好了...
- ...因為這真是一個漂亮的姑娘
- OK,,,
- ,,,'cause that is one fine-looking broad,
夠了，嘿﹗你...
All right, Hey! Would ya--
我...你在說的是我的女朋友
l me-
- You're talking about my girlfriend,
- 前女朋友，你說的
- 沒錯，但還是，這個...
- Ex-girlfriend, you said,
- Yeah, but still, it's,,,
拜托，我只是找點話題，
你知道的，男人間的閑聊
Come on, l'm just making conversation,
You know, guy-talk,
听著，我只是...我覺得不自在...
Look, l just,,, l don't feel comfortable
...跟一個完全陌生的人談論我的性關系
talking about my intimate relationships
with a complete stranger,
理解
Understood,
你知道嗎，如果要問你在談論性時有多保守
Well, you know, given how uptight
you are talking about sex,
你差不多已經給出了答案
you pretty much
answered the question,
我不保守﹗拜托﹗
l am not uptight! OK?
就因為我不愿意公開關于我前女友的性習慣...
Just because l don't feel like
revealing personal details
...的這些個人隱私，并不能說明我保守
about my ex-girlfriend's sexual habits
does not make me uptight,
我沒問你任何私人問題
l didn't ask you anything personal,
是嗎，那你認為他媽的什么才是私人問題﹖
Well, then, what the hell
do you consider personal?
這個，比如，你知道的，
如果我問你的那根棒子有多大
Well, it'd be like, you know,
if l asked you how big your rod was,
那么我就是百分之百的問過頭了
Then l would be
out of line, 1 00%%%,
不，不﹗這不比問我的女友是不是欲女更糟﹗
No, no! That is no worse than
asking me if my girlfriend's a nymph,
我只是問你她喜不喜歡性
l just asked you if she dug sex,
而且，如果我知道她是性冷感我就不會問了
Besides, l wouldn't have asked
if l'd known she was frigid,
她不是性冷感﹗
Yeah, well, she is not frigid!
你到底走不走﹖
Are you leaving?
噢，對了
Oh, yeah,
還有，能不能幫個忙﹖
And listen, Could you do me a favor?
- 不是什么大事
- 什么事﹖
- lt's no big deal,
- What?
我老爸的一個商業合伙人會過來取這個
A business associate of my dad's
is gonna come by to pick this up,
- 是冰凍牛排，是份禮物
- 不冷呀
- lt's frozen steaks, it's a gift,
- lt's not cold,
老爸說那家伙就是喜歡這個，你會怎么做﹖
Dad says that's the way the guy
likes 'em, What are you gonna do?
會幫我給他嗎﹖
Will you give it to him?
(doorbell)
請稍等
Just one second,
(doorbell)
- 奧德莉
- 湯姆
- Audrey,
- Tom,
走吧﹗快﹗
(man)) Let's go! Come on!
噢，這就對了，你跟他住在一起﹖
Oh, l guess this makes sense,
He's got you living with him now?
噢，不是，我只是在照看他的地方
- Uh, no, l'm just watching his place,
- (car horn))
- 他...杰克出了城
- 是嗎﹖
- He's,,, Jack's out of town,
- He is?
- 是的
- 噢，見鬼﹗
- Yeah,
- Aw, shoot!
我過來是希望討回我的工作
l came by 'cause l was
hoping to get my job back,
就是你害我失去的那份工作
You know, the one that
you got me canned from
只因為我泡了一杯難喝的咖啡﹖記得嗎﹖
'cause l made a bad cup
of coffee? Remember that?
听著，我真的很抱歉
Listen, l'm really sorry about that,
你怎么能只因為某個人
泡了一杯難喝的咖啡就解雇他，嗯﹖
How can you fire someone
for making a bad cup of coffee, huh?
我明白，這也正是我想跟他說的
l know, That's what l
tried to say to him,
你以為你是誰﹖他媽的Juan Valdez﹖
（Juan Valdez，哥倫比亞的咖啡品牌）
l mean, who do you think you are -
Juan fucking Valdez?
l might have had a future at that place
if you'd just give me half a chance,
只要你給我一半机會，說不定我就能
在那個地方干出些名堂來
- 我們快走吧，挂包﹗
- 噢，天吶，是我那笨蛋男朋友
- (man)) Let's get a move on, saddlebag!
- Oh, my God, That's my idiot boyfriend,
省口气吧，你這變態﹗
- (car horn))
- Hold your pants, you freakin' psycho!
老天，我快被他逼瘋了
God, He drives me crazy,
噢，嘿，既然你踩到地毯上了，
介不介意穿上這個﹖
Oh, hey, you know, since you're on the
rug, would you mind putting these on?
- 這些是醫用...我也穿了的
- 噢﹗甘草糖
- They're medical,,, l got 'em on, too,
- Ugh! Licorice,
我最恨甘草糖了，給我水，不然要吐了﹗
l hate licorice, l need water
or l'm gonna throw up, Ugh!
拜你所賜，我一個月內就失去了第二份工作，
現在是完全一文不名了
Thanks to you, l lost my second job
inside a month and now l'm flat broke,
你還丟過一份工作﹖
You lost another job?
是的，上禮拜五我剛丟了我的女服務生工作
Yeah, l got fired from my waitress job
just last Friday,
- 他們為什么解雇你﹖
- 噢，我不知道
- Why did they fire you?
- Oh, l don't know,
一個助理經理逮到我和顧客搞關系
One of the assistant managers
caught me making out with a customer,
- 什么﹖
- 嗯，實際上這個顧客...
- Excuse me?
- Well, l mean, actually the customer
...是我的男朋友
was my boyfriend,
我是說，我被解雇之后他成了我的男朋友
l mean, he became my boyfriend
after the incident anyway,
- 你這里有啤酒嗎﹖
- 嗯...嘿
- You got any beer in here?
- Uh,,, Hey,
- 找到了
- 穿上這個行嗎﹖
- Here we go,
- Would you mind putting these on?
這是這間房子里的規矩，哦，實際上，
這個規矩是很怪...呀...﹗
lt's a house rule, Oh, actually,
that's a twist,,, Aah!
這是柜台﹗听著，
杰克是個真正的偏執狂，這樣就好了
That's the counter, Listen, Jack,
is just a real stickler, That'd be great,
別說笑了，今天上午我就發現這一點了
No kidding, l found that out this morning,
我發誓，我要發瘋了，我要沖進去...
(man)) l swear l am gonna freak out
and l'm gonna come in there,,,
- 噢，老兄，斯派克真的發怒了
- 啊...
- Oh, man, Spike's in a real mood,
- Uh,,,
甚至不...嘿
- Don't even,,, hey,
- (doorbell)
- 快點，快點，快點，見鬼
- 我對天發誓，奧德莉
- Come on, come on, come on, Shit,
- (Spike)) l swear to God, Audrey,
我要在這家伙的門前尿尿﹗
l'll piss on this guy's front steps!
Let's go!
- (knocking))
- (doorbell)
你不立刻給我開門，我就撞進來...
lf you don't open this door this second,
l'm gonna come in there and,,,
嗨
- Hi,
- (burps))
別擔心，沒摔碎東西
- (clatter)
- Don't worry, Nothing broke,
嘿，寶貝，出來，你把我一個人
留在見鬼的車里，自己在做什么﹖
Hey, Baby, come on, What are you
doing leaving me in the goddamn car?
搖起你的屁股，寶貝，快點，我們該上路了
Shake that tail, baby,
Come on, Let's get a move on,
- 急什么，斯文點行不行﹖
- 奧德莉﹗
- Hold your horses, Try acting civilized,
- Audrey!
這是湯姆，我跟你說過的辦公室里那家伙
This is Tom, the guy that l was
telling you about from the office,
噢，那個咖啡小子
Oh, the coffee dude,
你以后會遭惡報的，超級怪胎﹗
You got some black ass karma
headed your way, superfreak,
噢，我們不需要你的說教，大人物﹗
Oh, we don't need no lecture
from you, Mr, High and Mighty,
嘿，閉上你的鳥嘴，小女人，
小心我把你扔到牆外
Hey, shut that sass-trap of yours, little
lady, before l bounce you off the wall!
听著，如果你愿意到外邊去吵，
我會感激不盡，拜托
Look, l would appreciate it
if you would take this outside, please,
嘿，如果你愿意出去給自己買個面包圈，
我會感激不盡，猶太佬
Hey, l'd appreciate it if you'd go
and buy yourself a bagel, Jewy,
猶太佬﹖我不是猶太人，而且我不認為取笑...
Jewy? l'm not Jewish, And l don't
think that making fun of the,,,
- 別理他，他是瘋子
- 我是瘋子﹖
- Don't pay attention to him, He's nuts,
- l'm nuts?
- 你以為你還能是誰﹖
- 听著，我們能不能到外邊去吵﹖
- Who do you think you are?
- Look, can we please take this outside?
噢，算了吧
Oh, come on,
你知道你是什么東西嗎﹖
你是個肮臟的妓女
You know what you are?
You're a filthy, little tramp,
我﹖那你和你那個女服務生又是什么呢﹖
Me? What about you and that waitress?
- 繼續走
- 我從未碰過她
- Keep going,
- l never touched her ever,
- 你發誓﹖
- 我敢對天發誓
- Swear?
- So help me God,
你敢用你媽媽的性命發誓﹖
You swear on your mama's life?
見鬼，我才不會用我媽媽的性命發誓
Hell, woman, l ain't gonna
swear on my mama's life,
- 為什么不﹖如果你說的是真話
- 我覺得他說的是真話，奧德莉
- Why not? lf you're telling the truth,
- l think he's telling the truth, Audrey,
那你為什么不用你媽媽的性命發誓﹖
Then why won't you swear
on your mama's life?
因為我覺得我沒有權利...
Well, because l don't feel
like l have the right
...拿我媽媽的性命來冒險，這就是為什么
to gamble with my mama's life,
that's why,
冒險﹖但是你顯然沒什么可擔心的...
Gamble? But apparently
you got nothing to worry about
...除非你象塊腐肉一樣在撒謊
unless you're lying like
a hunk of morgue meat,
嘿，我不想呆在這里被個婊子罵作大話王﹗
Hey, l ain't gonna sit here and get
called a liar by no skankin' whore!
你說誰是婊子﹖你這小蝦米雞巴的混蛋﹗
Who you calling a whore,
you shrimp-dick bastard?!
奧德莉，現在是你在激怒他了
Audrey, see now
you're just provoking him,
你這是惡意中傷的、完完全全的、
厚顏無恥的謊言﹗你明明知道﹗
That's a vicious, flat-out,
bold-faced lie and you know it!
- 是嗎﹖是嗎﹖我不這樣認為﹗
- 我現在就把雞巴亮出來﹗
- ls it? ls it? l don't think so!
- l'll whip it out right now!
- 不，不，不，我不想看
- 我現在就把雞巴亮出來...
- No, no, no, l don't wanna see it,
- l'm gonna whip it out right now
...証明給你看她是個說謊的婊子﹗
and prove to you
that she's a lying slut!
- 把你的那坨肉留在褲襠里吧﹗
- 你要看我的家伙嗎﹖
- Keep your meat in the fridge!
- You wanna see my piece?
- 好了，好了﹗夠了﹗
- 找把尺子來，湯姆﹗你去拿...
- All right, All right! That is enough!
- Go get me a ruler, Tom! You go get,,,
夠了﹗我對你是不是小蝦米雞巴不感興趣﹗
That is it, l don't care
if you have a tiny shrimp dick!
- 或者你有巨鯨雞巴，那個...
- 他媽的，奧德莉﹗
- Or a giant whale dick, which that's,,,
- Goddamn it, Audrey!
你跟他說是你在說謊，否則我砸爛你的臉，
我發誓﹗
You tell him you're a liar or l'm gonna
smash your face in, l swear!
- 等一下﹗放下這東西﹗
- 好了，我們能不能只用拳頭﹖
- Wait a minute! You put that down!
- All right, Can we please just use fists?
- 滾過來，你這小...
- 你打我，混蛋﹗
- Come here, you little,,, (slap))
- You hit me, you bastard!
- 我沒有打你，你胡說﹗
- 他打我﹗
- l did not and you know it!
- He hit me!
他明明打了我，就像我明明站在這﹗
He hit me as sure
as l'm standing right here!
- 你打了她﹖斯派克﹖
- 是的
- Did you hit her, Spike?
- Yes,
用手掌，只是用手掌
With an open hand,
lt was with an open hand,
- 用手掌又如何﹖
- 你不能...
- So what if it's open?
- You can't,,,
- 用手掌不算打
- 誰說的﹖
- Then it don't count,
- Says who?
任何人都這么說，你問這個猶太佬
Says anyone, Ask the Jew,
好了，夠了，你們兩個都該离開了
All right, that's it,
You two have got to leave,
行，沒問題，但是她休想和我一起走
All right, that's fine,
But she is not coming with me,
不歡迎你和我一起雙人行
You are not welcome in the double ride,
好啊，我才不在乎，我才不要坐你那破車，
我要留在這里和湯姆一起
Fine, l don't care, l don't need your lousy
trailer, l'll stay right here with Tom,
- 行，你和湯姆一起
- 我就留在這里
- Fine, Stay with Tom,
- l'll stay right here,
等一等，哇哦，兩位，你們需要
設法解決這件事
Wait a minute, Whoa, Guys, you need
to try to work this thing out,
- 他打了我﹗他打我屁股﹗
- 我知道，我知道
- He hit me! He knocked me on my can!
- l know, l know,
不過畢竟只是用手掌，而且...
Well, but it was with
an open hand after all, and,,,
兩人間的關系總是有高潮有低潮的
Relationships have their
ups and downs, you guys,
你們不想毀了這份很不錯的...
and you don't want to ruin this great,,,
(yelping))
噢，天吶，那只鳥，OJ﹗
Oh, God, The bird, OJ!
哦，我的天
Oh, my God,
(continues yelping))
噢
- (squeals))
- Oh,
你敢回來湯姆會踢爆你屁股﹗快滾吧﹗
You come back here or Tom's
gonna kick your butt! So take that!
噢，我嚇得發抖了，寶貝﹗
(revs engine)) Ooh, l'm shaking
in my boots, baby!
看看他們兩個，OJ
Look at those two, OJ,
(phone ringing))
噢，我不是逃跑，笨蛋﹗
(Spike)) Oh, l ain't
running away, dummy!
- 喂﹖
- 嗨，湯姆，你怎么樣﹖
- Hello?
- (Lisa)) Hi, Tom. How are ya?
- 嘿，麗莎，我很好，我很好
- Hey, Lisa, l'm great, l'm great,
- (squawks))
- 是OJ在叫嗎﹖
- 是的，是的
- ls that OJ?
- Yeah, yeah.
- 我們剛喝了點水
- 我已經有好几年沒听到他這樣尖叫了
- We just had a little drink of water,
- l haven't heard him squawk in years,
噢，是啊，他真是只瘋鳥，你知道的
Oh, yeah,
He's quite the crazy bird, you know,
是啊。總之，湯姆，我只想你知道...
Yeah. Anyway, Tom,
I just wanted you to know
今天晚上你讓我可以出來，
我真不知有多么感激你
how much I appreciate
you helping me out tonight.
不過今晚的派對結束后
我要去一個朋友那里睡
But l'd like to crash at a friend's place
tonight after the party,
如果我請求你今晚一整夜留下來，
你會不會覺得很恐怖﹖
Would you think it was horrible if l asked
you to stay the whole night tonight?
噢，嗯...我...我想你老爸不愿我留在這里
Oh, well,,, l-l don't think your dad
would want me staying here,
- 求你了﹖
- 好吧，我想我會留下來
- Please?
- Yeah, l suppose l could stay,
謝謝了，湯姆，我真的很感激你，
明天見
Thanks, Tom. I really appreciate it.
See you tomorrow. (hangs up))
我不怕你，湯姆當然也不怕你﹗
(Audrey)) l ain't afraid of you and Tom
sure as hell ain't scared neither!
笨蛋﹗沒用的家伙﹗
Butthead! Loser!
(tires screeching))
噢，謝天謝地，他終于走了，
嘿，我今晚留在這行嗎﹖
Oh, my God, Thank God he's gone,
Hey, so is it OK if l stay here tonight?
噢，這...這又不是我的房子
Oh, man, it's,,, it's not even my house,
噢，沒錯
Oh, yeah,
算了，我也不想要什么施舍
OK, Well, l sure as hell
don't want any charity,
我的意思是，你并不欠我什么，所以...
l mean, it's not like you
owe me anything, so,,,
今天在辦公室發生的事情我很抱歉
And l'm sorry about
that whole office thing,
我知道你不想我被解雇
l know that you didn't mean
to get me fired,
- 是的，你不該被解雇
- 謝謝
- Yeah, You didn't deserve to get fired,
- Thanks,
好了
OK,
我想我只能出去找一間無家可歸者的收容所了
Well, l guess l'll just go try
to find a homeless shelter then,
- 等一等
- 怎么﹖
- Wait a second,
- Yeah?
天吶
(sighs)) God,
- 听著，我想你可以留下來
- 真的﹖噢，謝謝你，湯姆
- Look, l suppose you can stay,
- Really? Oh! Thanks, Tom,
你人最好了，噢，我會打掃廚房的，好嗎﹖
You're the best, Oh, and l'll
clean up the kitchen, OK?
- 好
- 好，好
- OK,
- OK, OK,
- (doorbell)
- (knocking))
來了，等一下
(Tom)) Yeah, One second,
有人敲門
- (knocking))
- There's somebody at the door,
嗨，嗯，有什么事﹖
Hi, Uh, can l help you?
瓦克斯派我來取一個包裹
Vasquez sent me here
to pick up a package,
噢，你是...對對對，
萊德跟我說過你會來
Oh, you're the,,, Yeah, yeah, yeah,
Red told me you might be stopping by,
啊...噢，嗨，我是湯姆
Uh,,, Oh, hi, l'm Tom,
這算什么，奧普拉﹖
他媽的把包裹給我就行了
（奧普拉.溫弗莉，頭號脫口秀女主持人）
What is this, Oprah ?
Just give me the goddamn package,
噢，好的，對，嗯...
Oh, OK, Yeah, Um,,,
我想這個就是了
l think this is it,
如果這東西不是真的，我就折斷他的拇指
lf this ain't kosher,
l'm gonna break his thumbs,
噢，按照規定，包裹上面應該印有戳記
Oh, well, by law, it should be stamped
right on the package there,
怎么...
- (. classical)
- What,,,
(squawks))
- 噢，晚飯時間到了，伙計
- Oh, Dinnertime, buddy,
- (. classical continues))
OJ...今天的特餐是一份美味的老鼠肉自助餐
OJ,,, today's specials include
a scrumptious buffet of mice kebabs,
噢，見鬼，啊...糟了
- (squawks))
- (gasps)) Aah! Shit! Ah,,, crap!
你這混蛋
You son of a bitch,
哈
- (squeaks))
- Ha,
(grunts))
我逮到你了，伙計
- (chuckles)) l got you now, buddy,
- (squealing))
啊
(gasps)) Aah!
Aah! (groans))
(squawks))
- 老兄，好酷啊
- 噢，老天
- Dude, that was cool,
- Oh, my God,
- 湯米，對那些古董溫柔點
- Tommy, easy on the antiques,
- (squawking))
- 那是只貓頭鷹﹖
- 沒錯，OJ跑了，他怎么會飛了﹖
- Was that an owl?
- Yes, OJ got out, How is he flying?
- 他是一只鳥
- 他...不，杰克說過他...
- Well, he is a bird,
- He,,, no, Jack said that he,,,
啊，見鬼﹗我得找到他
Aw, shit! l gotta find him,
別著急，也許他餓了會自己回來
Don't worry, He'll probably
come back when he's hungry,
不，我得找到他，要不然我會失業﹗
你知道嗎﹖
No, l have to find him or l'm gonna
lose my job! You know what?
這也是幫你討回工作的好机會
This isn't gonna help your chances
of getting your job back either,
好吧
OK,
- 他死哪去了﹖
- 湯姆，放輕松點
- Where the hell is he?
- Tom, relax,
放輕松﹖OJ跑了﹗
（注﹕習慣上把愛顯淑女派頭的女孩稱為OJ，
而loose有放蕩之義，所以"OJ's loose"這句話
引起身后三個女孩的誤會）
- Relax? OJ's loose!
- (gasping%screaming))
- 現在可沒時間輕松﹗
- 湯姆﹗他就在那﹗
- This is no time to relax!
- Tom! He's right over here!
- 那邊，那邊，那邊﹗
- OJ﹗
- Right there, right there, right there!
- OJ!
- 就在那﹗
- OJ﹗
- Right there!
- OJ!
站住﹗不，不，站住，別跑﹗
Stop! No, no, Stop, Stop,
OJ，OJ...
OJ, OJ,,,
站起來，你在我的地頭做什么﹖想打劫我﹖
Get up, What the hell you doing
on my property? Planning to rob me?
不，我...我只是在找...
No, l-l was just looking for,,,
是，是，我看見你在找的東西了，
你很喜歡年輕姑娘﹖
Yeah, yeah, l see what you're looking
for, You got a thing for young girls, eh?
不是
No,
那你為什么一直打量我老婆，你這變態﹖
Then why do you keep
eyeing my wife, you perv?
你的...不，我沒有看，我...
Your,,, no, l wasn't looking, l,,,
亞瑟，你很快過來嗎﹖我需要你幫我
Arthur, are you gonna be back soon?
l need you to spot me,
再等一會，寶貝
Just give me a minute, honey,
- 噢，請不要殺我
- 我不會殺你
- Oh,,, Please don't kill me,
- l'm not gonna kill you, OK,
只要你不殺我，我把我最值錢的東西給你，拿去
lf you let me live, l'll give you my
most valued possession, Here, take it,
你知道這是什么嗎﹖
You know what that is, don't you?
- 伊万德.霍利菲爾德的耳朵
- 什么﹖
- Evander Holyfield's ear,
- What?
就是被麥克.泰森咬下來的那一塊耳朵
The part of the ear that
Mike Tyson bit off and spit out,
- 但這是白色的
- 那又如何﹖
- But it's white,
- So?
- 不應該是黑色的嗎﹖
- 如果還長在他腦袋上，沒錯，應該是黑的
- So, shouldn't it be black?
- Well, if it's still on his head, sure,
但誰都知道切下來的耳朵會褪色
But anybody knows that a
severed ear loses its color,
- 才不會
- 謝樂爾?
- No,
- Sheryl?
- 什么事?
- 一只耳朵...
- Yeah?
- What happens to an ear
- ...從你腦袋上切下來之后會怎么樣﹖
- 會變色
- if it's severed from your head?
- lt changes color, Duh,
噢，見鬼﹗
- (thud)
- (Sheryl) Ow! Damn!
蒂娜，給我一瓶啤酒
- (Audrey)) Tina, give me a beer,
- (man laughs))
你肯定是耍我
- (Tina)) Oops,
- (man)) You have got to be kidding me,
- 再來一次
- 來吧，你們這些家伙﹗
- (Audrey)) Try another one,
- (Tina)) Come on, you guys!
開派對了﹗
- (clatter)
- (Tina)) Party!
- 來吧，我們開派對﹗
- 奧德莉...
- Come on, let's go!
- Audrey,,,
- 他媽的這里是怎么回事﹖
- 抬頭
- What the hell is going on in here?
- Heads up,
這些人是誰﹖
Who are these people?
我請了几個朋友來幫忙找貓頭鷹
l invited some friends over
to help us look for the owl,
德瑞爾還修好了客廳里的桌子
And Darryl even fixed
the table in the hall,
- 謝謝
- 杰克甚至不會發現桌子摔坏過的
- Thank you,
- He won't even know it was broken,
三不沾﹗
- (bottle breaks))
- (man)) Air ball,
那個我們待會處理，各位，這是湯姆
We'll get that later,
Everyone, this is Tom,
- 你好，湯姆
- 嗨，各位
- Yo, Tom,
- Hi, guys,
各位，湯姆真是個好人，他的困難會...
You guys, Tom's a real good guy
and his nuts are gonna just,,,
奧德莉，能不能...
Audrey, could you,,,
- 什么﹖
- 听著，我很感謝你的幫助
- What?
- Listen, l appreciate all your help,
但是你能讓你的朋友呆在房子外頭嗎﹖
But could you make sure that your
friends stay out of the house?
- 他們所有人還是黑色那家伙﹖
- 不，是他們所有人
- All of them or just the colored guy?
- No, all of them,
噢，這招真高，這樣那個黑色的家伙
就不會以為是針對他個人了
Ooh, that's smart, That way the
colored guy won't take it personal,
- 我根本就沒有針對...听著
- 什么﹖
- l have nothing against,,, Look,
- What?
我有責任照看好這所房子
l am responsible for this house
我不能讓所有這些人在這里閑逛
and l can't have all of these
people hanging around,
好的，我明白了，各位，我們出去
OK, all right, l got it,
You guys, let's move it out,
- 啊，我才剛開始呢
- 好主意
- Aw, l was just getting started,
- Good idea,
謝了，各位，太好了
Thanks, guys, That's great,
- 蛋糕怎么辦﹖
- 別緊張，他們都是好人
- (Tina)) What about the cake?
- Don't worry, they're all good people,
他們不會偷東西，也不會象印第安人一樣喝醉酒
They're not gonna steal nothing
or drink too much like the lndians,
听著...務必要讓他們呆在外頭
Look,,, just make sure they stay outside,
- 好嗎﹖
- 好的
- OK?
- OK,
(door opens%shuts))
- 麗莎﹖
- 嗨，湯姆
- Lisa?
- Hi, Tom,
啊，你回來了﹖你怎么回來了﹖
Uh, you're home?
Why are you home?
不值得再提，我和漢斯大吵了一架
lt's not worth going into,
l got in a huge fight with Hans,
哦，那么...分手了﹖
Oh, So,,, it's over?
跟一個我老爸喜歡的家伙約會，
是我自己的錯
lt's my own fault for dating
a guy my dad likes,
是嗎﹖
Really?
是的，漢斯是他的高層市場經理之一，
你知道的，所謂的哈佛法學院畢業生，
Yeah, he's one of his top marketing
execs, You know, Harvard Law,
良好的家庭背景，
鄉村俱樂部里一流的网球好手
Comes from a good family, top
of the tennis letter at the country club,
- 湯姆，我能和你談談嗎﹖
- 奧德莉﹖
- Tom, can l talk to you for a second?
- Audrey?
是的，她來找你老爸說點事
Yeah, She came to,
uh, talk to your dad,
好吧，我要進房間了，你喜歡就留下來
OK, l'm gonna go in my room,
You could stay if you want,
好
OK,
- 湯姆﹖
- 奧德莉，我馬上過來，行了嗎﹖
- Tom?
- Audrey, l'll be right there, OK?
行
OK,
- 你走也可以
- 或許我們可以談談...
- Or you could go,
- You know, maybe we could talk,,,
...遲點
,,,later,
這個怎么樣﹖
Here, How about this one?
- 什么事﹖
- 我們找到貓頭鷹了﹗
- What's going on?
- We found the owl!
- 在哪里﹖
- 哦，他跑了
- Where is he?
- Uh, well, he got away,
- 去哪了﹖
- 他跳到矮樹叢中去了
- Where'd he go?
- He hopped somewhere in the bushes,
- 沒錯
- 你在干什么﹖
- That's right,
- What are you doing?
弄點碎牛肉，這是誘鳥的好法子
Getting hamburger meat,
That's a good way to lure birds,
- 他們喜歡碎牛肉﹖
- 我不知道，我沒養過鳥
- They like hamburger meat?
- l don't know, l've never had a bird,
- 但大部分動物都對肉感興趣
- 的确如此
- But most animals respond to meat,
- lt's a fact,
要幫忙分肉嗎﹖
Wanna help me separate the meat?
史彼得，跟湯姆說說肯尼迪遇刺真相
Speed, tell Tom about
the Kennedy assassination,
真是很酷，湯姆，因為史彼得知道
誰殺了約翰.肯尼迪
This is so cool, Tom, 'cause Speed
knows who killed JFK,
不，問他呀﹗湯姆，你問他
No, ask him! Tom, ask him,
- 問他是誰殺了肯尼迪
- 好吧，好吧
- Ask him who killed him,
- All right, All right,
- 誰殺了肯尼迪﹖
- Desi Arnaz
（美國50年代電視劇集“我愛露西”男主角演員）
- Who killed JFK?
- Desi Arnaz,
- 噢
- 他的生活從此不一樣了
- Oh,
- His life just changed,
(squeaking))
噢
Oh,
噢，天吶，噢，噢，噢
Oh, God, Oh,,, oh,,, oh,,,
- 湯姆﹗
- 見鬼，麗莎
- Tom!
- (gasps)) Shit, Lisa,
- 哦，你來這里干什么﹖
- 這里是我的儲物室
- Uh, what are you doing in here?
- This is my closet,
噢，噢...嗯，有東西跑到我褲子里了
Oh, Oh,,, uh, l had
something in my pants,
我在給那鳥喂老鼠，
結果老鼠溜到我褲子里了
Um, l was feeding the mouse to the bird
and he, uh, ran down my pants,
不好意思...
- (mice squeaks))
- l'm sorry that, uh,,,
噢，快看，它在那，那邊，進臥室了
Oh, look! There it is!
That way! The bedroom,
- 哇哦，當心﹗
- 啊﹗
- (Lisa)) Whoa, Watch out!
- Aah! (groans))
- 噢，老天，你沒事吧﹖
- 是的，是的，我沒事
- Oh, my gosh, Are you OK?
- Yep, Yep, l'm good,
別著急，我們會抓到它的
Don't worry, we'll get it later,
哦，我來幫你
Oh, here, Let me help you,
你知道嗎，我真的很高興你留下來，
今天晚上我正需要多笑笑
You know, l'm really glad you stayed,
l needed a good laugh tonight,
謝謝，哇哦，能讓我出個
更大的洋相來逗你笑嗎﹖
Thanks, Wow, Yeah, could l make
a bigger ass out of myself?
- 想喝一杯嗎﹖
- 哦，不用了，謝謝
- (chuckling)) Do you want some wine?
- Uh, no, thanks,
噢，好的
Yeah, sure,
- 干杯
- Cheers,
噢，天吶，那是沃特.佩頓的簽名海報﹖
Oh, my God, ls that signed
by Walter Payton?
是啊，85年的熊隊是橄欖球運動史上最偉大的球隊
（85年芝加哥熊隊打進季后賽并攻入超級杯）
Yeah, ''Sweetness'', '85 Bears, Only the
greatest team ever to play the game,
沃特.佩頓、Jim McMahon、Mike Singletary
Shut up, Walter Payton,
Jim McMahon, Mike Singletary,
你知道嗎﹖或許你就是有史以來最酷的女孩
You know what?
You may be the coolest girl ever,
- 你喜歡橄欖球﹖
- 是啊，我愛死它了
- You like football?
- Yeah, l love it,
我不知道你們還喜歡橄欖球
l didn't know you guys liked football,
當然喜歡，我和保羅每個禮拜天都去看球賽
Yeah, No, me and Paul
watch the game every Sunday,
- 保羅也喜歡﹖
- 是啊
- Paul, too?
- Yeah,
噢
- Oh,
- (chuckles))
噢，這是什么﹖
Oh, what's that?
哦，沒什么，只不過是我以前畫的東西
Oh, it's nothing,
lt's just something l used to do,
畫得真的很棒，我不知道你還是個畫家
That is really good,
l didn't know you were an artist,
我以前畫畫，不過再也找不到朋友
愿意當我的裸体模特了
l used to be, but l couldn't get any more
of my friends to pose nude for me,
- 你不會有興趣吧，嗯﹖
- 哦...
- You wouldn't be interested, would you?
- Uh,,,
你害羞了，我開玩笑的
You're blushing, l was just joking,
我沒有害羞，是我...我的臉有時候會自己變紅
l'm not blushing, l just-l just
get red from time to time,
你真搞笑
You are so funny,
不過，說正經的，你真應該繼續畫下去，
我覺得你畫得很好
No, seriously, you should really
pursue this, l mean, you're good,
我倒是想，但是這背离了
我老爸給我安排好的道路
l would, but it doesn't really fit in
with my father's plan for me,
我是午夜貓頭鷹出版社的未來
Future of Midnight Owl Publishing,
噢，看，它在那
- (mice squeaks))
- Oh, look! There it is,
- 就在那，鑽過門了
- 我們會抓住它的，我們會抓住它的
- He's right there, Through the door,
- We'll get him, We'll get him,
哇哦﹗當心﹗
- Whoa! Watch out!
- (groans))
- 你沒事吧﹖
- 你老爸會殺了我的
- Are you OK?
- Your dad's gonna kill me,
不會，不用擔心，這是我哥的，我爸不在乎這個
No, don't worry about it,
lt's my brother's, My dad won't care,
噢，萊德
Oh, Red,
- 哦，我爸告訴你了﹖
- 告訴我什么﹖
- Oh, so Dad told you?
- About what?
- 禁制令
- 怎么回事﹖
- The restraining order,
- How's that?
是的，萊德被禁止靠近我、靠近我爸
或靠近這所房子的100碼范圍
Yeah, Red's not allowed within
他...他沒有...他沒有提這件事
He,,, uh, he didn't-he didn't mention that,
萊德是個怪人。如果我爸發現任何人
進了這所房子，尤其是萊德
Red's a freak, You don't want
to be around my dad if he finds out
那個時候，你絕對不想呆在我爸身邊的
anyone was in this house,
especially Red,
好像萊德無論走到哪里都會制造麻煩
lt's like wherever he is, there's trouble,
有一次，我爸出城了，他趁机開了個大派對
l mean, one time, he had this big party
'cause Dad was out of town
結果我爸提早回來...
and my dad came home early,,,
嘿，哦...這個，既然老鼠跑了，
我們回房去好不好﹖
Hey, uh,,, you know, since the mouse is
gone, what say we, uh, go back inside?
好的
OK,
(grunts))
(both screaming))
(. synthesizer)
- 它還准備參加奧斯卡﹖我討厭它﹗
- 我知道﹗
- lt was up for an Oscar? l hated it!
- l know! (laughing))
噢，我討厭那部電影﹗老兄，我真不敢相信
Oh, l hated that movie!
Man, l can't believe you,
你像是...你跟你工作時候的樣子太不一樣了
You're like,,, you're so different
from how you are at work,
我該怎么做﹖穿著沃特.佩頓運動衫走來走去﹖
What am l gonna do? Like, walk around
with my Walter Payton jersey?
不，不，我懂，就像是，
工作的時候你必須是麗莎.泰勒﹕
No, no, l get it, lt's, like, at work
you have to be Lisa Taylor:
你知道的，一個對家族企業全心全意的員工
the, you know, loyal employee
to the family firm,
而我必須是...湯姆...
And l have to be,,, Tom,,,
湯姆.斯坦菲爾德﹕愿意為任何人做任何事的家伙
Tom Stansfield: the guy
who will do anything for anybody,
沒錯，就是我
Yup, That's me,
真的，好像我可以和你聊任何事
l swear, it's like l can just
talk to you about anything,
我知道，确切地說，這...
l know, exactly, lt's,,,
- 這有點瘋狂
- 是啊，是有點
- Yeah, this is crazy,
- Yeah, it is,
我猜是因為咱倆互相沒有吸引力，知道嗎﹖
l guess it's because there's no
attraction between us, you know?
是
Yeah,
這樣就不會有性壓力
You know, there's none
of that sexual tension,
- 是的
- 你就像是我的女性朋友
- Yeah,
- lt's like l'm with a girlfriend,
- 很棒吧，是不是﹖
- 是的
- lt's great, isn't it?
- Yeah,
也許我們可以一起逛街、購物
l mean, maybe we could go to the mall
sometime and go shopping,
- 那樣一定很有趣﹗是不是﹖
- 是的
- That would be fun! Wouldn't it be fun?
- Yeah,
等一下，你該听听這首歌
Wait, you have to listen to this song,
來呀，我要跟人跳舞﹗
Come on, l need
someone to dance with!
你不會想看我跳舞的
- You don't want to see me dance,
- (. ''You Make Me Feel Like Dancing')
- 來呀，和我一起跳
- 我完全不懂怎么跳
- Come on, dance with me,
- l have no idea what l'm doing,
來呀，把手握在一起，對了，現在轉圈
Come on, Put your hands together,
Yeah! Now go underneath,
- 怎么...象這樣﹖
- C?
- What,,, like this?
- Yeah!
- 象這樣﹖
- C?
- Like that?
- Yeah! (squeals))
停一停，看我的，看我的
Hold on, hold on,
Watch, watch, watch,
噢
- (pants rip))
- Oh,
- C∴?..
- 我真是不自量力
- Yeah! Oh,,,
- l'm trying to do too much,
噢﹗C?
(laughing)) Oh! Yeah!
我是個舞蹈家
- (squealing))
- l'm a dancer,
- 接著我
- 噢...干嘛﹖
- Catch me,
- Oh,,, what?
(squeals))
- 我接住你了﹗
- 哇哦﹗
- l got you!
- Whoa!
哇哦
Whoa,,, (chuckles))
噢，我要死了
OK, l am doomed,
過來
Here,
(. ''Better Man'' by Martina Sorbara))
噢，我好喜歡這首歌
Oh, l love this song,
我朋友珍妮配著這首歌跳很狂野的脫衣舞...
My friend Jenny does this
really wild strip routine
...給他男朋友看，真是超級性感，
就算是你也會很欣賞的
for her boyfriend to this song,
lt's super sexy, Even you'd appreciate it,
我真希望能夠象她一樣，你知道嗎﹖
她是多么自由自在啊
l wish l could be like her, you know?
She's so free and everything,
(giggles))
(giggling))
覺得怎么樣﹖
So, what do you think?
哦，很...很好看
Ah, it's,,, it's, uh, very nice,
那么，要不是你是個同性戀，
這已經讓你興奮了，是嗎﹖
So if you weren't gay,
this would turn you on, right?
- 同性戀﹖誰說我是同性戀﹖
- 我老爸說的，你是說你不是﹖
- Gay? Who said l was gay?
- My father, You mean it's not true?
- 不是﹗
- 不是﹖天吶，太難為情了﹗
- No!
- No? God, l'm so embarrassed!
- 我不敢相信你害我做這种事﹗
- 我不是故意...我是說，嗯...
- l can't believe you'd let me do this!
- l didn't mean to,,, l mean, um,,,
為什么你爸爸說我是同性戀﹖
Why would your father say that l'm gay?
我不知道，不過，你不能完全怪他，
我的意思是，你确實有點女性化
l don't know, Well, you can't blame him
entirely, l mean, you are a little feminine,
別難過
- (gasps))
- Don't be hurt,
沒關系的
lt's OK,
漢斯也有點女性化
Hans is a bit of feminine, too,
話說回來，漢斯到底做了什么﹖
What exactly did Hans do anyway?
倒不是他做了一件什么事
Well, it's not like
he did just one thing,
而是信任的問題
lt's more about trust,
是的，信任是...是蠻重要的
Yeah, Trust is,,, it's important,
信任是最重要的
Trust is everything,
我不知道，也許是我的原因，
可能是我給人某种感覺
l don't know, Maybe it's me, lt's like
l'm just sending out some kind of vibe,
- 象樣的男孩都不會喜歡我
- 不是的
- l can't attract a decent guy,
- No,
- 我哪里不好﹖
- 你根本就用不著擔心
- What's wrong with me?
- Don't even worry about it,
你很快就會有新的男朋友
You're gonna find another guy so fast,
看看你自己，多么迷人啊
l mean, look at you,
You're amazing,
- 你真這么想﹖
- 你以為今晚我為什么會來這里﹖
- You really think so?
- Why do you think l'm here tonight?
噢，天吶，湯姆
Oh, God, Tom,
原來你不知道，你以為是...
You didn't know,
You thought that,,,
(door opens))
嗯...嗯...我要...我馬上回來
Uh,,, uh,,, l'm gonna,,, l'll be right back,
我出去一下，看看奧德莉是不是需要毛巾
l'm just gonna go and check
and see if Audrey needs towels,
湯姆，你沒必要對我撒謊
Tom, you don't have to lie to me,
如果你要上廁所，盡管去，快點回來就是了
lf you have to go to the bathroom,
go take a crap and come back,
(chuckles))
(clatter)
怎么...嘿﹗見鬼，你在這里做什么，老兄﹖
What the,,, hey! What the hell
are you doing here, man?
(grunts))
你妄想從瓦克斯身上詐兩万塊錢，
居然還問我在做什么﹖
You try to bone Vasquez out of 20 grand
and you ask me what l'm doing?
你以為我是在“Mrs. Fields”干活嗎﹖
你以為我的老板喜歡烤餅干嗎﹖
（“Mrs. Fields”，著名曲奇餅干企業）
You think l work for Mrs, Fields? You
think my boss likes to bake cookies?
- 哇哦﹗你這是干什么﹖別這樣
- 你竟然賣面粉給我
- Whoa! What are you doing? Come on,
- You tried to sell me flour,
面粉﹖我...我根本就不知道你在說什么...
你在干什...別這樣﹗
Flour? l-l don't even know what
you're talk,,, What are you,,, Come on!
听著，我只是幫我老板照看房子的
Look, l'm just housesitting for my boss,
- 你老板是誰﹖
- 杰克.泰勒
- Who's your boss?
- Jack Taylor,
杰克.泰勒﹖我跟一個叫杰克.泰勒的
在Joliet一起坐過牢
Jack Taylor, huh? l did time
in Joliet with a Jack Taylor,
是不是中等身高、頭發不長不短、
屁股上生了嚴重的毛囊炎﹖
Average height, medium hair,
horrible case of folliculitis on his ass?
- 我不可能知道他有沒有毛囊炎
- 我想你說了他是你老板
- l wouldn't know about the folliculitis,
- l thought you said he was your boss,
- 沒錯
- 那你就從沒見過他屁股﹖
- He is,
- And you never saw his ass?
- 為什么我會見到我老板的屁股﹖
- 這是顯而易見的
- Why would l see my boss's ass?
- lt stands to reason,
你給一個人干久了活，遲早...
You work for a guy long enough,
sooner or later,
...有机會瞅到他的屁股
you're gonna get a glimpse of his ass,
听著，我...我不知道你是干哪行的
Listen, l-l don't know
what line of work you're in,
但是我從未見過我老板的屁股
but l've never seen my boss's ass,
嘿，老兄...
Hey, man,,,
嘿﹗嘿，住手，否則我要報警了﹗
Hey! Hey, stop it
or l'm gonna call the cops!
跟他們說什么﹖說你的毒品買賣搞砸了﹖
And tell them what?
Your drug deal went bad?
你敢出賣我，我就剁了你，象只火雞一樣
You rat me out, l'm gonna
carve you up like a turkey
再用剁剩下的你去砸你的小孩
and beat your kids
with what's left of you,
- 我沒有小孩
- 我可以等
- l don't have any kids,
- l can wait,
(. cell phone ringing
''Fur Elise'' by Beethoven))
失陪。喂﹖沒錯，好的
Excuse me, Hello? Right, OK,
湯米，別怪我沒說清楚
Tommy, let's get clear on something,
一個小時后，要么讓我拿到
瓦克斯付了錢購買的貨
ln the next 60 minutes, l'm gonna
bring Vasquez what he paid for
要么把你的卵蛋包好充數
or your gift-wrapped nuts,
(door shuts))
- 噢，嗨，湯姆，怎么了﹖
- 對，我正要問你
- Oh, hi, Tom, What's going on?
- Yeah, That's what l wanna know,
你老爸的禮物是怎么回事﹖
你看...看到那家伙沒有﹖
What's going on with your dad's gift?
See,,, Do you see that guy?
他要殺我﹗
He was gonna kill me!
你不覺得是你反應過度了一點嗎﹖湯姆﹖
Don't you think you're
overreacting a little, Tom?
反應過度﹖這家伙拿著把刀﹗
我可不覺得是我反應過度
Overreacting? The guy had a knife!
l don't think that l am overreacting!
他可能只是找錯地址了
He probably just had the wrong address,
我是說，光在芝加哥就有不止一打人叫杰克.泰勒
l mean, there's gotta be over a dozen
Jack Taylor's in Chicago alone,
我要進我爸的臥室了，
這家伙還來的話你叫我
l'm gonna go to my dad's bedroom,
You tell me if the guy shows up again,
行，有你的，你听著
All right, All right,
You listen to me,
你根本就不應該出現在這所房子里
You're not even supposed
to be in this house,
誰說的﹖
Says who?
我知道禁制令的事了，萊德
l know about the restraining order, Red,
禁制令，我想那是個天大的誤會
Restraining-shmaining, l mean,
that's just a big misunderstanding,
湯姆﹗找到OJ了﹗
(Audrey)) Tom! lt's OJ!
(overlapping chatter)
噢
(Audrey and friends)) Oh,,,
- 哇，嘿，你是誰﹖
- 我來找麗莎，我叫漢斯
- Whoa, Hey, Who are you?
- l'm here to see Lisa, My name's Hans,
- 讓你很震惊﹖
- 沒有
- ls that so shocking?
- No,
怎么了，你很奇怪她跟我這樣的人約會﹖
What, you surprised she'd go out
with someone like me?
不，不，不是...
No, no, lt's not,,,
得了吧，老兄，你該感到羞恥
Give me a break, man,
You oughta be ashamed of yourself,
我告訴你，外面有大把的女孩...
Let me tell you something,
There are a lot of girls out there
...不在乎我剛好...
who can see past the fact
that l just happen to be,,,
...超重了几磅
a few pounds overweight,
你知道嗎，我的內心和別人是一樣的
(crying)) You know, inside
l'm just like everyone else,
- 我給你拿紙巾
- 謝謝
- Let me get you a tissue,
- Thank you,
- 今天是我重新開始節食的第二天
- 嘿，漢斯...
- l'm on the second day of a new diet,
- Hey, uh, Hans,,,
- 我連巧克力都不吃了
- 我真的很抱歉
- l gave up chocolate,
- l'm really sorry,
我想，嗯，我們之間只不過有個不太好的開始
l think that, uh, we just
got off on the wrong foot,
哦...很高興見到你，漢斯，我是湯姆
Oh,,, uh,,, lt's good
to meet you, Hans, l'm Tom,
我，嗯...
l, uh,,, (clears throat)
我是麗莎的...朋友
l'm just a friend of Lisa's,
哦，很好啊，或許你可以幫我，她在嗎﹖
麗莎﹗麗莎﹗
Oh, great, Well, maybe you can
help me, ls she here? Lisa! Lisa!
哇哦，漢斯，跟你說
Whoa, Hans, you know what?
現在可能不是你見麗莎的好時机
Maybe right now isn't a great time
for you to see Lisa,
怎么樣，要不要喝一杯﹖
What say, uh, we get you a drink?
噢，好吧，沒錯，她可能真的很生气
Oh, OK, Yeah, she's
probably really upset,
你知道嗎，今天晚上我和她之間有誤會，
結果她拂袖而去
You see, we got in a misunderstanding
tonight and, well, she left me,
- 哇哦，真不幸
- 是啊
- Wow, that's unfortunate,
- Yeah,
是怎么回事﹖
Uh, what happened?
哦...我想是因為她從背后看到我那樣
光著身子，有點被嚇到了
Well, l think seeing me naked from
behind like that kind of shocked her,
噢，那么，今晚是你們頭一次﹖
Oh, So, tonight was the first time,
是的，今晚是頭一次，真可怕
Yeah, Tonight was the first time,
lt was awesome,
我當時象這樣躺在床上，一條腿翹在空中
l mean, l was lying up on the bed like
this with one leg straight up in the air,
- 我想我不需要看...
- 我一只手這樣摸著屁股
- l don't think l really need to see,,,
- And l had a handful of ass right here,,,
- 哇哦
- ...另一只手握著這玩意（奶子）
- Whoa,
- ,,,and l had a handful of this,
漢斯，別這樣，哇哦，
老天，你...那個
Hans, please, Whoa,
God, you're,,, that's,,,
- 這個時候麗莎走了進來
- 什么﹖
- And that's when Lisa walked in,
- What?
她逮到我在和別的女孩鬼混
She caught me in
the bed with a blonde,
什么﹖
What?
噢，算了吧，老兄，
難道你從不想和女孩做這檔事﹖
Aw, come on, man, Tell me you
haven't ever wanted to do it with a,,,
漢斯，漢斯，不是的...是你欺騙了她
Hans, Hans, No,,, you cheated on her,
你知道嗎，湯姆﹖你說得對
You know something, Tom?
You're right,
噢，我猜那真的是欺騙，這下我要失去所有人了
Aw, l guess that was cheating,
And now l've gone and lost everyone,
一開始我就應該知道這是不對的
l should have known
from the start it wasn't right,
她一直跟我說我讓她想起她老爸
She kept telling me
l reminded her of her dad,
漢斯，你必須認識到你們之間
已經完蛋了，你知道嗎﹖
Hans, you gotta realize
that this is over, you know?
你應該做個了斷，然后...然后繼續前進
And you gotta put an end to it,
and-and move on,
- 去一個更好的地方，知道嗎﹖
- 對
- And get yourself to a better place, OK?
- Yes,
- 我想你明白我的意思
- 是的，我确實明白你的意思
- l think you know what l mean,
- Yeah, l do know what you mean,
我准備好了，我知道我該怎么做了
And l'm ready, l know
what l have to do,
我想該說再見了
Well, l guess this is good-bye,
OJ!
- (squawking))
- OJ!
謝謝你，湯姆
(Hans)) Thanks, Tom,
OJ，回來﹗
(Tom)) OJ, come back!
(dog barks))
OJ﹗
OJ!
(squawks))
你好，你一定是茱莉的約會對象
進來，進來
Hello, You must be Julie's date,
Come in, Come in,
事實上，我只是來找一只鳥的
Actually l'm just here looking for a bird,
別拘束，阿爾伯特，茱莉還在准備
Make yourself at home, Albert,
Julie's still getting ready,
- 不，事實上，我的名字叫湯姆
- 抱歉，我耳朵不好使
- No, actually, uh, my name is Tom,
- l'm sorry, l'm hard of hearing,
- 你能說大聲點嗎
- 我的名字叫湯姆﹗
- Could you speak up, please?
- (shouts)) My name is Tom!
我肯定茱莉說過你叫阿爾伯特
l could've sworn Julie
said your name was Albert,
不，你看，恐怕是你弄錯了
No, see, l'm afraid that you're mistaken,
- 有人來了﹖
- 是的，他是茱莉的約會對象，阿爾伯特
- ls someone here?
- Yes, This is Julie's date, Albert,
- 啊﹗啊﹗
- 這是我外甥，喬治
- Ah! Ah!
- This is my nephew, George,
- 他眼睛瞎了，腿也殘廢了
- 哦，哦...很高興見到你
- He's blind and crippled,
- Oh, Uh,,, (shouts)) nice to meet you,
我不是聾子
l'm not deaf,
失陪一下，我去看看茱莉怎么還沒下來，
她可能太緊張了
Excuse me, l'll go see what's
keeping Julie, She's probably nervous,
你就是茱莉要約會的家伙，嗯﹖
So you're Julie's date, huh?
不，我是...我只是來，我在找一只貓頭鷹
No, l'm just,,, l just came here,
l was looking for an owl,
你不必找什么無聊的借口
(laughs)) You don't have
to make lame excuses,
听著，你知道作為一個殘廢的人有什么优勢嗎﹖
Listen, do you know what the
advantage is in being a cripple?
不，我不知道
No, l can't say that l do,
你不會真的在乎我說什么，對嗎﹖
You don't really care to hear much
what l have to say, do you?
不，不，不是這樣的，我...
No, no, lt's not that, l'm,,,
你知道嗎﹖請說下去，我洗耳恭听
You know what?
Go ahead, l'm listening,
坐下，湯姆
Sit down, Tom,
你知道我殘廢了之后得到了什么嗎﹖
You know what l gained
by becoming a quad?
你在搖頭﹖我又看不到，你該知道﹗
What, are you shaking your head?
l can't see, you know!
對不起，嗯...嗯...告訴我
你得到了什么
l'm sorry, Uh,,, uh,,,
Tell me what you gained,
我不再需要偉哥了
l no longer need my Viagra,
現在我能夠保持興奮好几個小時
Now l can maintain
my arousal for hours,
這...這棒极了，我想正所謂...
That's-that's great,
l guess things have a way
...失之東隅，收之桑榆，對嗎﹖
of evening themselves out
in the long run, huh?
不，不完全是，你知道為什么嗎﹖
No, not really,
And do you know why?
不知道，為什么﹖
No, why?
因為我是個瞎了眼、廢了腿的怪物，笨蛋﹗
Because l am a blind,
quad freak, you moron!
怎么，你以為女人會喜歡我這樣的﹖﹗
What, you think women dig this?!
- 我是說，你以為女人...
- 噢，你好
- l mean, you think women go,,,
- Well, hello,
“我要給那個變种怪胎我的電話號碼”﹖
,,,''l wanna give that mutant
freak my number''?
- 我是肯.摩哈斯，茱莉的爸爸
- 嘿，很高興見到你
- Ken Morehouse, l'm Julie's dad,
- Hey, nice to meet you,
喬治又說他那些自怜的廢話來煩你了嗎﹖
ls, uh, George boring you
with his self-pitying tripe?
- 廢話...
- 不，一點也不
- Tripe,,,
- No, not at all,
“我是瞎子，我是瘸子，等等等等”
''l'm blind, l'm crippled, Boohoo-hoo,''
离開這個房間，我要和阿爾伯特單獨談談
Leave the room, l wanna talk
to Albert alone for a second,
- 我愛呆在哪就呆在哪
- 离開這個房間﹗
- l can stay if l want,
- Leave the room!
- 好吧，好吧
- 出去﹗
- OK, OK,
- Get out!
- 你用不著怒气沖沖
- 快出去﹗出去﹗
- You don't have to be huffy about it!
- Get out now! Get out!
- 好
- 轉彎，轉彎，轉彎
- OK,
- Turn it, turn it, turn it,
噢，老天
- Oh, for God's sakes,
- (clatter)
- 真是不好意思
- 他媽的誰把這東西擺在這﹖
- l'm so sorry,
- (George)) Who the hell put that there?
- (cat meows))
- (thud)
我女儿還要几分鐘才能好，你...你先坐，阿爾伯特
My daughter's gonna be a few minutes,
Have a-Have a seat, Albert,
- 湯姆
- 不，我叫肯
- Tom,
- No, Ken,
- 沒錯，你叫肯
- 是的
- Right, You're Ken,
- Yes,
在你說什么之前，阿爾伯特，
我只想讓你知道，茱莉...
Before you say anything, Albert,
l just want you to know that Julie
...真的很在意她的容貌，
自從那次...那次意外之后
is really self-conscious about her
appearance since the,,, the accident,
好的...
- (door shuts))
- Right,,,
- 噢，茱莉
- 茱莉，這位是阿爾伯特，
阿爾伯特，這是茱莉
- Oh, Julie,
- Julie, this is Albert, Albert, Julie,
- 見到你真好，阿爾伯特
- 哇哦，見...哇哦
- lt's nice to meet you, Albert,
- Wow, lt's,,, wow,
見到你我也很高興，
不過，事情是這樣的，我不是阿爾伯特
lt's nice to meet you, too,
But, the thing is, is that l'm not Albert,
- 也就是說我不是你在等的人
- 噢
- That is to say that l'm not your date,
- Oh,,
這是個天大的誤會
There's been a giant misunderstanding,
- 噢，你怎么能這樣﹖
- 我就知道會這樣﹗
- Oh, how could you?
- (crying)) l knew this would happen!
不，我說的是實話
No, l'm telling the truth,
是茱莉不夠漂亮嗎﹖GQ先生﹖是不是﹖
（《GQ》雜志，男性時尚雜志）
Julie wasn't pretty enough
for you, Mr, GQ? ls that it?
- 不，你不明白
- 噢，我明白，“法比奧”
（法比奧，可能是指一個著名封面男模）
- No, you don't understand,
- Oh, l understand, Fabio,
- 你傷害了這個可怜的女孩
- 不不，我不是...
- You broke that poor girl's heart,
- No, no, See, l'm not,,,
你以為茱莉是白痴嗎﹖
你以為是她接受你恩賜的童話故事嗎﹖
Do you think Julie is an idiot? Do you
think she bought your little fairy tale
先生，穿著醫用鞋套很迷人嗎﹖
Mr, l'm Too Sexy
for my medical booties?
- 噢，這...
- 滾出去
- Oh, th,,,
- Get the hell out of here,
再不滾我就把你的英俊屁股踹到天上去
Or l'll kick your pretty-boy ass
to kingdom come,
- 有什么事被我打斷了嗎﹖
- 沒有，只不過...
- Am l interrupting something?
- No, it's just that the,,,
- (squawks))
- (grunts))
湯姆，有兩件事我們得談談
Tom, there's two things
that we need to talk about,
什么事﹖
What?
首先，我再也不要穿著這些鞋套了
First of all, l don't wanna
wear these booties anymore,
- 沒人穿著這樣的鞋套
- 行
- No one else is wearing the booties,
- Fine,
- 還有呢﹖
- 蒂娜認為她得了癌症
- What's the other thing?
- Tina thinks she's got cancer,
- 你摸到沒有﹖
- 嗯，我剛...
- Do you feel it?
- Uh, l'm just,,,
- 這儿會有什么東西嗎﹖我沒有...
- 看到沒有，蒂娜﹖
- What's supposed to be there? l don't,,,
- See, Tina?
左邊一點，這附近
Move your hand to the left,
Now move it around,
噢
Uh-huh,
- 你沒有感覺到有東西嗎﹖
- 是的，我是說，沒有，沒有
- Don't you feel anything?
- Yeah, l mean, no, no,
沒有，它好像...嗯...
No, it seems to be,,, Well,,,
蒂娜，你的乳房和我的毫無區別，行了嗎﹖
Tina, your breast is no
different than mine, OK?
- 就是有，你又沒比過
- 湯姆，摸摸我的乳房，比一比
- lt is, There's no comparison,
- Tom, feel my breast and compare,
現在你發現我們兩個的乳房有什么不同嗎﹖
Now, do you detect any difference
between our breasts?
- 嗯...你們別太急
- 好舒服
- Well,,, You gotta slow down a little,
- lt sure feels good,
嗯，你的乳房...
- Well, yours is a,,,
- (door opens))
- 麗莎，這不是你看到的那么回事
- 我信了你說的每句話
- Lisa, this isn't what it looks like,
- l believed everything you said,
我是在...
l'm,,,
全都只是甜言蜜語，是嗎﹖
lt was all just a
bunch of lines, wasn't it?
不，不，麗莎，都是...
我向你發誓，每字每句都是真心的
No, no, Lisa, it was all,,,
l swear to you, l meant every word,
這...這里什么事都發生
This is,,, nothing's going on here,
很好，湯姆，真高興你認為
我是個完完全全的白痴
Great, Tom, l'm glad you think
l'm a complete idiot,
不，不，我告訴你，
我是在給她們檢查乳腺癌
No, no, l'm telling you, l was just
checking these girls for breast cancer,
- 你讓我惡心
- 不，麗莎，等等﹗
- You make me sick,
- No,,, Lisa, wait!
- 她絕對不會原諒我了
- 她當然會原諒你
- She's never gonna forgive me,
- Of course she will,
這是你第一次對她不忠﹖
ls this the first
time you cheated on her?
是的，不﹗我...慢著﹗
Yeah, No! l,,, yeah,,, wait,
我沒有對她不忠，老天，你在場的呀﹗
l didn't cheat on her, l mean,
you were there for God's sakes!
听著，我知道你沒有對她不忠
Look, l know that
you didn't cheat on her,
- 我是說，你剛才是有點貪婪，不過...
- 我...
- l mean, you were a little grabby, but,,,
- l,,,
听著，你不覺得我們應該先找到貓頭鷹...
Look, don't you think
we should just find the owl
...再來擔心你的風流韻事嗎﹖
and worry about your little ''affair'' later?
我...我要...我要發狂了，可我不想發狂
l,,, l am get,,, l'm getting angry
and l don't get angry,
- 噢﹗
- 嘿，史彼得﹖
- Ugh!
- Hey, Speed?
嘿，我能問你個問題嗎﹖
Hey, can l ask you a question?
- 你在干...我以為你走了
- 我是走了...去拿這個
- What are you,,, l thought you left,
- l did,,, to get this,
- 好吧，爐火怎么著了﹖
- 很暖和，是吧﹖
- All right, Why is the fire going?
- Cozy, isn't it?
- 好吧，你放下那玩意
- 逼我呀
- All right, You put that down,
- Make me,
行﹗
All right,
嘿﹗嘿﹗放下撬棍﹗
Hey! Hey! Put the crowbar down!
不然我轟爆你的屁股﹗
Or l will blow your ass to fucktown!
對了
That's right,
- 你威脅不了我
- 但是...我有槍
- Don't you ever threaten me,
- But,,, l got a gun,
- 你干什么﹖
- 湯米，我們都有槍
- What are you doing?
- Well, Tommy, we both have guns,
唯一的不同是，你沒膽子用你的槍
Only difference is, you don't
have the guts to use yours,
噢，是嗎﹖什么讓你這么有把握﹖
Oh, yeah?
Well, what makes you so sure?
噢，我很有把握
Oh, l'm sure,
(trickling))
噢﹗噢，天吶，怎么...
你怎么回事﹖瘋了嗎﹖
Oh! Oh,,, Jesus! What the,,,
What are you, out of your mind?
住手，你瘋了嗎﹖
- (phone ringing))
- Stop that! Are you crazy, man?!
(chimes))
- 喂﹖
- 斯坦菲爾德，有什么情況要報告嗎﹖
- Hello?
- (Taylor) Stansfield. Anything to report?
先生﹗嗯，一切順利，一切...都在我掌控之下
Sir! Uh, everything's great,
l got,,, everything's under control,
- OJ喝了足夠多水嗎﹖
- 哇哦﹗
- Did OJ get enough water?
- (TJ)) Whoa!
嗯，OJ...什么﹖噢，是的
Uh, OJ,,, What? Oh, yes,
杰克，請稍等一下。
我要轟掉你的雞巴
Uh, Jack, could you hold on?
l'm gonna shoot your pecker off,
我不打算整個周末都呆在外面
I don't plan on being away
the entire weekend.
- 我恨你﹗我恨你﹗
- 我可能...
- l hate you! l hate you!
- It's possible I may be
...提早回家，所以你務必要确保一切正常
coming home early, so make sure
that everything's in order.
老天﹗
Jesus!
噢，有件事忘了跟你說
Oh, something I forgot to tell you.
- 先生﹖
- 那個魚缸，水有點淺
- Sir?
- The fishtank. It's a little low.
- 我馬上就處理
- 很好
- l'm taking care of that right now,
- Good.
我回來之后，要跟你談談創意部的那個職位
When I get back, I want to talk to you
about that position in Creative.
- 啊﹗
- 先別激動
- Aah!
- Don't get excited yet.
我沒說你已經得到那個職位了，
不過我們會討論這個問題
I didn't say you had the job.
We'll discuss it.
噢，謝謝，先生，太好了，再見
Uh, thank you, sir, Uh, great, Bye,
真他媽見鬼﹗
Holy shit!
我...
l just,,,
小子，我撒完尿了，你這有什么喝的嗎﹖
Boy, l'm tapped out,
You got anything to drink?
廚房里有，謝了
ln the kitchen, Thanks,
該死﹗
Dammit!
哇哦﹗這里發生什么事了﹖
湯姆，你出了個小事故﹖
Whoa! What the hay happened in here?
Tom, did you have a little accident?
或許你該試試凱格爾鍛煉法，
好讓你底下那玩意收緊點
（凱格爾鍛煉，用于鍛煉恥尾肌，治療尿失禁）
You might wanna try a few Kegels,
Kinda tighten it up down there,
- 夠了﹗
- 我現在就練練，先松弛一下
- That's it!
- l'm doing 'em right now, And release,
嗯，入鄉隨俗吧...
Well, when in Rome,,,
噢，“Canada”
- (trickling))
- . Oh, Canada
“杰克.泰勒，Rectacid(藥名)，臀部用藥”
''Jack Taylor, Rectacid,
Apply liberally to buttocks as needed
“可減輕紅斑及其它毛囊炎症狀”
to reduce redness
and other symptoms of folliculitis,''
混蛋
Son of a bitch,
- 你尿到自己身上了﹖
- 不，我沒有
- Did you piss yourself?
- No, l did not piss myself,
- 看起來像是你尿到自己身上了
- 我說了我沒有
- Looks like you did,
- Well, l didn't,
是樓下那個瘋子干的
lt was that maniac downstairs,
我們必須在他拆了這房子之前阻止他
We gotta stop him before
he tears this house apart,
你知道該怎么做嗎﹖給他吃顆這种小玩意
You know what you gotta do?
Give him one of these little babies,
- 這是什么﹖
- 安眠藥
- What's that?
- lt's a sleeping pill,
我從史彼得那搞來的，給你，
藥效很強的，小心點
l got 'em from Speed, Here,
So strong, so be careful,
- 很強勁的東西
- 好了，就一顆
- lt's powerful stuff,
- Here, Just one,
要小心
Be careful,
嘿，打扰了
Hey, Excuse me,
我只想跟你道歉，剛才拔槍對著你
You know, l just wanted to apologize
for pulling that gun on you earlier,
我真是太過分了
That was totally out of line,
嘿，我還不知道你叫什么
Hey, you know, l don't
even know your name,
- 我叫TJ
- TJ﹖好名字
- l'm TJ,
- TJ? That's nice,
我想我剛才也做得過分了，到處尿尿
l guess maybe l was out of line
by pissing all over everything,
不過，老兄，真的很有趣
Man,,, that was funny, (laughs))
C　乙幌螄不抖褡　紓　愫鵲氖裁矗?
Yeah, l've always enjoyed a good prank,
What are you drinking there?
威士忌，要不要來點﹖
Whiskey, You want some?
這里的酒多的是
There's plenty of booze
around here, that's for sure,
好的，我來點波旁酒
Yeah, l'll take a shot of bourbon,
- 噢，天吶，哇哦﹗
- 怎么了﹖
- Oh, my God! Wow!
- What?
哇哦﹗看那兩個美女在...
Whoa! Look at those
two blondes going at,,,
- 噢，是三個﹖
- 在哪﹖
- Oh, wait, are there three of them?
- Where?
她們正干得火熱，就在那邊二樓
They're going at it right up there
on the second floor,
- 你哪里看到的﹖
- 就在...噢，老兄，她們走了
- Where are you looking?
- Right th,,, uh,,, Oh, man, they left,
(chuckles))
見鬼，弄得我這么興奮
Damn, l was all psyched up
for some action,
女同性戀真是很特別的
Lesbians are very special,
噢...嘿，我們為這個干一杯，嗯﹖
Oh,,, Hey, l'll drink to that, huh?
- 干杯
- 好的
- Cheers,
- All right,
嗯
Mmm,
噢，你是不是...
- (grunts))
- Oh, are you,,,
- 哇哦
- 給我，我為何不...
- Whoa,
- Here, Why don't l,,,
哇哦﹗哇哦
- (glass breaks))
- Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa,
(steps on glass))
哇哦
- Whoa,
- (gong))
奧德莉﹖
- Audrey?
- (babbling))
奧德莉﹗
Audrey!
天吶﹗他像個人体振動按摩器
(gasps)) Oh, my God!
He's like a human vibrator,
什么...他是怎么回事﹖
What,,, All right,
what is wrong with him?
- 我不知道，你偷偷給他吃了藥﹖
- 是的
- l don't know, Did you slip him the pill?
- Yes,
那一定是藥起作用了
Then that must be it then,
你不是把藥溶在威士忌里給他喝的吧﹖
You didn't give him the pill
with whiskey, did you?
- 是啊
- 噢，不﹗
- Yeah,
- Oh, no!
- 你不該把這兩樣溶在一起
- 奧德莉，你沒跟我說過﹗
- You're not supposed to mix the two,
- Audrey, you did not tell me that!
任何人都知道不該把藥和酒溶在一起﹗
Everyone knows that you're not
supposed to mix booze with pills!
- 拜托﹗
- 好了，他會沒事嗎﹖
- Come on!
- OK, ls he gonna be OK?
別擔心，他會好的，我曾經是醫護人員
Don't worry, He'll be fine,
l used to be a paramedic,
- 湯姆﹖我想我發現OJ了
- OJ﹖我才沒空管...
- Tom? l think l found OJ,
- OJ? l don't care about,,,
我們這里出事了，奧德莉，打911﹗
We have a situation here,
Audrey, call 91 1 !
- 我跟你說了，他會好的
- 你肯定﹖
- l'm telling ya, he'll be fine,
- Are you sure?
- 他只要休息一會，我肯定
- 好吧，你看著TJ，用這個
- He just needs some rest, l'm positive,
- OK, You watch TJ, Use this,
沒有裝子彈，不過他不知道
lt's not loaded, but he doesn't know that,
噢，拜托﹗
- (doorbell)
- Oh, man!
- 噢，嘿
- 我是茱莉
- Oh, hey,
- Julie,
- 來自...
- 隔壁街區的，沒錯
- From,,, yeah,
- Down the block, That's right,
我可以進來嗎﹖
You mind if l come in?
就這樣，你抓住他的腳踝
(Audrey)) All right,
You grab his ankles,,,
我們不如去那邊那個房間
Why don't we go
to that room over there?
- 好，我抓住這頭
- 噢，他好重
- (Speed) OK, yeah, l got this end,
- (Audrey)) Man, he's heavy,
我可以坐下嗎﹖
Do you mind if l sit down?
- 哦，當然可以
- 謝謝
- Uh,,, yeah, Sure,
- Thank you,
噢，嘿，抱歉打攪你們了，
嗨，我是萊德
Oh, hey, Sorry to
butt in, Hi, l'm Red,
- 嗨，幸會
- 幸會
- Hi, it's nice to meet you,
- Nice to meet ya,
是這樣，我那個真的約會對象來了后，
我才知道你說的是實話
Anyway, l realized you were telling
the truth when my real date showed up,
- 當然他沒有留下來
- 只能說他是個笨蛋
- Of course he didn't stick around,
- Well, that guy is a bum,
我肯定不是因為你
Well, l'm sure that had
nothing to do with you,
不，我知道是我的原因
No, l know it did,
即使在出事之前，我也沒吸引過任何男孩
l've never had any guys attracted to me,
even before the accident,
絕對不可能
Now that cannot be true,
大約半年前，我在路上搭了便車
Well,,, about six months ago,
l was hitchhiking
結果卡車司机想強奸我，除此之外...
and a trucker tried to rape me,
but other than that,,,
拜托，你是告訴我你從未交過男友﹖
Come on, You're gonna tell me,
you never had a real boyfriend?
嗯，只有一次，不過我認為他只是可怜我
Well, once, but l think
he just felt sorry for me,
你和他交往了多久﹖
Oh, well, uh,,, how long did that last?
大約6年，然后有一天，他就那么走了
Um,,, about six years
and then one day, he just left,
- 有別的女人﹖
- 不，他被巴士車撞了
- Another woman?
- No, He got hit by a bus,
你看，并不是你的原因
(Red) Well, see that's not your fault,
但他好像沒有很努力去避開那輛巴士
Well, he didn't seem to try
very hard to avoid the bus,
我想他就是想逃离我們這段關系
l think he just wanted
out of the relationship,
茱莉，你為何不坐這張椅子﹖
Julie, why don't you sit in this chair?
噢，我開始覺得有點頭暈了
Oh, geez, l'm starting
to feel a bit woozy,
(blood squishes))
好了，我得去找OJ了
OK, All right, l
have to go find OJ,
萊德，如果你能幫我看著點，就太好了
So, Red, if you could watch things
for me, that'd be great,
沒問題
Got ya,
听著，我認為你對自己太苛刻了
Look, l think you're being
way too hard on yourself,
而且，我打賭有很多男孩曾被你吸引
l mean, besides, l bet there've been a lot
of guys who've been attracted to you,
不，他是唯一一個
No, he was the only one,
還有那個卡車司机呢﹖顯然你迷住他了
What about that trucker? l mean,
he was obviously attracted to you,
我想當時無論是誰那個司机都會強奸
(sighs)) l think the trucker probably
would have raped anyone,
我很怀疑，也許他認為你特別漂亮
l doubt that, You were probably
pretty special to him,
你真好，萊德
(chuckles)) So sweet of you, Red,
我也不是要煩你，我是說真的
l'm not just jerking
your chain either, l mean it,

- (giggles))
- Yeah, (chuckles))
- 你們動這草坪干什么﹖
- 沒什么，湯姆，我們只是想埋了TJ
- What are you doing to the lawn?
- lt's OK, Tom, We just had to bury TJ,
埋...什么﹖你是說，他...
Bury,,, what? You mean, he's,,,
你說過他會沒事的，我以為你曾經是醫護人員
You said he was gonna be OK!
l thought you were a paramedic,
- 我是上過醫護方面的課
- 你上過...你...你們...
- Well, l took a course,
- You took,,, you-you guy,,,
你們不能就這么埋了他﹗
You can't just bury him, you guys!
我們可不會把他放到我車里
Well, we're not gonna
put him in my car,
- 沒錯
- 好了，別說了，我打911
- (Audrey)) That's right,
- All right, Forget it, l'm calling 91 1 ,
- 那是需要急救才打的
- 你認為這是什么情況﹖
- That's for emergencies,
- What do you think this is?
這家伙已經死了，過20分鐘，他仍然是死人一個
The guy's dead, ln 20 minutes,
he's still gonna be dead,
叫急救車來沒有意義
- There's no sense of urgency here,
- (chuckles))
不，我們必須報警，跟警察報告這件事
No, we have to call the cops
and report it!
- 跟他們怎么說﹖
- 說事實﹗發生了一次意外
- And tell 'em what?
- The truth! That there was a,,, accident,
- 他們可能不那么看
- 面對現實吧，湯姆，是你殺了他
- They might not see it that way,
- Let's face it, Tom, You did kill him,
- 是你給我那种藥
- 嘿，我沒有叫你殺死任何人，拜托﹖
- You gave me the pill,
- Hey, l didn't tell you to kill nobody, OK?
但你沒告訴我不能用威士忌﹗
Well, you didn't tell me
not to use the whiskey!
- 如果你听我說了...
- 你根本就沒有提威士忌﹗
- Well, if you'd listen to me,,,
- You didn't say anything about whiskey!
我以為你會听我的
- (whistles))
- l would think you would listen to me!
沒時間互相推諉了
There's no time for blame games,
你何不鋪些樹葉﹖讓它看上去更自然
Why don't you spread around
some leaves? Make it look good,
我不會幫你藏匿一具尸体﹗
l am not gonna help
you conceal a dead body!
嘿，你們不覺的我們該說點什么嗎﹖
Hey, you know what? Don't you
think we should say something?
- 什么﹖
- 她說得對
- What?
- You know what? She's right,
最后的儀式或者頌詞，或者類似的玩意﹖
Some kind of last rites or eulogy
or something like that?
- 我要暈了
- 我們是該說几句
- l'm so screwed,
- We should say something,
好了，好了，說吧，赶快
Fine, fine, You know what? Say
something, Get,,, just make it quick,
主，今天我們下葬TJ，他是...
Lord, this day we lay to rest TJ,
who was, uh,,,
- 我真的不了解他
- 我也不了解他
- l really didn't know him,
- l don't know him,
湯姆，你是最了解他的，不如你來說吧﹖
l mean, Tom, you know him the best,
Why don't you say something?
- 我﹖
- 是的
- Me?
- Yeah,
我只知道這家伙是個狂暴的殘忍的暴徒，
而且對女同性戀很感興趣
All l know is that the guy was a violent,
sadistic goon that was into lesbians,
阿門
Amen,
- 湯姆﹖
- 麗莎
- Tom?
- Lisa,
- 我不敢相信你還在這里
- 听著，求你了
- l can't believe you're still here,
- Listen, please,
你必須听我解釋
You have to let me explain,
听著，湯姆，今晚只是個錯誤，僅此而已
Look, Tom, Tonight was just a
big mistake, That's all there is to it,
不，你...你看到的我和那兩個女孩的事情，
都只是怪异的巧合罷了
No, you,,, that,,, what you saw with
the girls, all that was was weird timing,
萊德﹖萊德來這里干什么﹖
Red? What's Red doing here?
萊德﹖噢，萊德剛好在附近
Red? Oh, uh, Red
was in the neighborhood
他順便路過這里
and he-and he stopped by,
不過，你看，今晚并沒發生什么
真的很糟糕的事情
But, you see, nothing really
bad happened tonight,
- OJ不見了是因為他嗎﹖
- 不，不是，嗯...OJ沒有拴好
- ls he the reason OJ's gone?
- No, No, uh,,, OJ got loose,
這是個小問題，不過我們會找到他的
And that's a little problem,
But we're gonna find him,
而且我們正在找他，所以...
And we're looking for him, so,,,
這是什么﹖
What's this?
哦，湯姆殺了一個人，我們在掩埋他的尸体
Oh, uh, Tom killed a guy
and we're burying the body,
- 好吧，這件事挺糟糕的
- 啊﹗
- OK, that was bad,
- Aah!
現在是你反應過度了，并不是...
OK, well, now you're
overreacting, lt's not,,,
- 噢﹗
- 啊﹗
- Oh!
- Aah!
(all yelling))
好了，好了，嘿
All right, all right, hey,
誰敢動一動，她的腦袋上就會有個大洞
Anybody moves, there's gonna be
a big hole where her brain used to be,
是嗎，動手呀，開槍呀
Yeah, Go ahead, shoot,
你還等什么﹖動手呀﹗
Well, what are you waiting for?
Come on!
你還等什么﹖﹗干掉這婊子﹗
What are you waiting for?!
Waste the bitch!
- 湯姆﹗
- 不，我才不在乎﹗
- Tom!
- No, l don't give a shit!
- 嘿，我可不是說笑，混蛋
- 是嗎﹖
- Hey, l'm not joking, asshole,
- Yeah?
扣扳机呀，來呀，來呀﹗
Pull the trigger, Come on, Come on!
我看你是光說不練
l think you're just all talk,
看來我們兩個都有槍啊
Looks like we both got guns,
這次誰會先開槍﹖
Who's gonna shoot first this time?
(chuckles))
(groans))
這樣應該可以了吧
(Red) Well, that should do it,
湯姆﹗你太勇敢了
Tom! You are so brave,
不，不，根本沒什么大不了的，
這支槍根本沒裝子彈...
No, no, lt's not even that big of a deal,
This gun's not even loaded,,,
- (gunshot)
- (grunt)
見鬼這是怎么回事﹖
(man)) What the hell is going on?
我真不應該怀疑你，
你為了我，拿你自己的命來冒險
l never should have doubted you,
You risked your life for me,
奧德莉在廚房里找到一些子彈，
可能被我重新上到槍里了
Audrey found some bullets in
the kitchen and l may have reloaded it,
沒錯，是我上的
Yeah, l did,
各位，打扰一下，誰認識一個叫杰克.泰勒的人嗎﹖
Yo, excuse me, Does anyone here
know a Jack Taylor?
什么事﹖
Why?
這小子剛打電話來，說如果
我不在15分鐘內赶到火車站接他...
This dude just called, said if l don't pick
him up at the train station in 1 5 minutes,
...我就要失去工作了，你覺得這是怎么回事﹖
l'm out of a job, What do
you suppose that means?
噢，天吶
Oh, my God,
我也是這么想的，因為我根本就沒有工作
That's what l thought,
'cause l ain't got no job,
- 他提早回家了
- 好了，別擔心
- He's coming home early,
- OK, don't worry about it,
一切有我，好嗎﹖相信我，你只要別開車太快了
l'll take care of everything, OK?
Trust me, Just don't drive too fast,
知道了
Got it,
還有，或許你該把這東西收好
And, um, maybe you
should put that away,
噢，天吶
Oh, God,
(. ''Go Home'' by Barenaked Ladies))
噢
Ooh,
(squeaks))
(sighs))
(. whistling))
我就知道是你
l knew that was you,
(beer bottles clank)
既然禮拜一下午我們要去泰國開會
(Taylor) As long as we're in Thailand
for the meeting on Monday afternoon,
好的，可以趁我們在夏威夷加油時帶上它
Yeah, We can pick it up
when we refuel in Hawaii,
嘿，要不要先停車，喝點東西...
Hey, uh, do you wanna stop
and, uh, get something to drink,
...或者上一下洗手間什么的﹖
go to the bathroom or something?
我們現在就把各部門頭頭帶過去
We'll take the departmental heads now
几個禮拜后再讓創意小組過去
and the Creative team
in a couple of weeks,
(squeaks))
那是午餐前的行程安排，然后是午餐...
That's the agenda up to lunch,
then there's lunch,,,
(squawking))
好的，那么...
- OK, And then,,,
- (squawks))
- (horns honk)
- (tires screech))
行，行
OK, OK,
行，好的
OK, fine,
- 斯坦菲爾德，你在干什么﹖
- 沒什么，先生
- Stansfield, what are you doing?
- Nothing, sir,
請稍等
Hold on a moment, please,
斯坦菲爾德，你為何不專心開你的車...
Stansfield,,, why don't you
just concentrate on the driving
讓我繼續打我的電話﹖
and let me get
on with making my call,
- 等等﹗
- 又怎么了，斯坦菲爾德﹖
- Wait!
- What is it now, Stansfield?
噢，沒什么，先生，快到家了
Oh, nothing, sir, Almost home,
- 嘿，這東西怎么跑進去了﹖
- 小心那玩意
- Hey, How'd this get in there?
- Oh, be careful with that,
我會小心的，是我發現的好東西
l will, Good thing l found it,
處理一把手槍可以有几种方法
There's several ways to properly
dispose of a handgun,
但不包括把槍扔到垃圾袋里
none of which include
putting it in a garbage bag,
不許動﹗警察﹗不許動﹗
(cop over megaphone))
Freeze! Police! Freeze!
放開那女孩﹗舉起雙手﹗
Let go of the girl
and put your hands in the air!
你被徹底包圍了，TJ﹗
You're completely surrounded, TJ!
放下武器，把手放在頭上﹗
Put down your weapons
and put your hands on you head!
不，你們弄錯了，他不是TJ，
我是麗莎.泰勒，這是我老爸的房子
No, you guys, Wait, He's not TJ,
l'm Lisa Taylor, This is my dad's house,
小姐，我們接到多宗報案
Ma'am, we've received
numerous reports
說這一帶發生了行竊、槍擊...
from this neighborhood: theft, gunfire,,,
行了，听著，我知道你們可能
以為我們殺了某個人
All right, Look, l know you probably
think we may have killed somebody,
但是湯姆并不知道他會毒倒那個家伙
but Tom didn't know
he poisoned the guy,
我們埋葬他的時候以為他死了，
不過他現在看上去好的很
and we thought he was dead when
we buried him, But he seems OK now,
只是他的頭上，被我們用鏟子
打了的地方，流了一點血，
His head's just a little bloody
from where we hit him with the shovel,
我發誓湯姆開槍的時候并不知道槍里上了子彈
And l swear when Tom shot the gun off,
he didn't think it was loaded
是我把子彈上回去的，
所以只要你們都進來...
'cause l put the bullets back in,
so if you'll all just step inside,
...就知道這里沒有任何人死了
you'll see there's nobody dead here,
他可能暫時有點呼吸困難
He may have had the wind
knocked out of him temporarily,
不過只要經過一點緊急護理，
我想他就會沒事的
but with a little first aid,
l think he'll be just fine,
(screaming))
- (screams))
老天爺﹗
Holy mother of God!
漢斯﹗
(Lisa)) Hans!
是的，我知道，我知道
Yes, l see, l see,
行，好的
- (squeaks))
- OK, fine,
噢﹗
- (squawking))
- Whoa!
能再說一次嗎﹖信號不好﹗
Could you say that again?
You're breaking up!
請稍等，OJ﹗
One moment, please, OJ!
(tires screeching))
我不懂你為什么要這樣做，漢斯，你怎么想的﹖
l just can't understand why you would
do this, Hans, what were you thinking?
他會沒事的，也許會有點喉嚨痛
He'll be fine, He may complain
about a sore throat,
不過他的情況比這吊燈可好多了
but he's in a lot better shape
than this chandelier,
等這家的主人回來，我可不愿再呆在這里
Well, l'd hate to be here
when the owner gets back,
你可以到時候再說一次
You can say that again,
哇哦
- (man)) Whoa!
- (car horn))
- 湯姆﹗爸爸﹗
- 又怎么了﹖
- Tom! Daddy!
- What do we got?
- 怎么回事﹖
- 當心玻璃，大家小心
- What was that?
- Watch the glass, OK, everybody?
- 我們把他們從車里弄出來
- 噢，天吶，爸爸﹗
- Let's get 'em out of the car,
- Oh, my God! Daddy!
- 大家退后，保持鎮靜
- 你們都沒事吧﹖
- Everybody, stay back and remain calm,
- (Lisa)) Are you all right?
就是他，就是他透過矮樹叢窺視我
That's him, That's the one spying
on me through the bushes,
他開槍打碎了我女儿茱莉的臥室窗戶
He shot the bullet right through
my Julie's bedroom window,
來呀，告訴他們，茱莉
Here, Tell 'em, Julie,
你們過來，湯姆要把這家伙放在這
You guys, Tom wants the body in here,
慢慢來，放我下來
- (TJ)) Take it easy, Put me down,
- (gasps))
斯坦菲爾德，你做了什么好事﹖
Stansfield, what have you done?
麗莎，收拾行李，你跟我一起去泰國
Lisa, pack your things,
You're coming with me to Thailand,
不行﹗
No!
把他帶走﹗
（Get his ass out of here）
Get his ass out of here,
你還提“屁股”這詞，真是好笑，杰克
lt's funny you should mention
the word ''ass'', Jack,
為何我們不先說說你的事﹖
Why don't we start
by talking about yours,
你說什么﹖
Excuse me?
麗莎，你爸爸不是你想象的那樣子
Lisa, your father is not
who you think he is,
整個出版業務，是一個巧妙的掩護
The whole publishing operation,
lt's a great cover,
你是怎么辦到的﹖你怎么弄的﹖
把書挖空﹖
Now how'd you do it? What'd you do?
Did you hollow out the books?
噢，還把工厂設在泰國，真是天才﹗
Oh, and locating the plant
in Thailand, lt's genius!
- 你都在說些什么﹖
- 我說的...杰克
- What are you talking about?
- What am l,,, Jack,
你知道嗎，我一直相信你，杰克，
直到遇見這個人
You know, l-l would've believed
you, Jack,,, until l met this man,
他好像對你的底細很了解
who seems to know a lot about ya,
認得這個嗎﹖我听說它對治療毛囊炎
非常有效
Recognize this? l hear it's very
effective in relieving folliculitis,
我沒生毛囊炎
l don't have folliculitis,
他讓我別無選擇
He's given me no choice,
- 他讓我別無選擇﹗
- 湯姆，你干什么﹖
- He's given me no choice!
- Tom, what are you doing?
- 這太瘋狂了﹗
- 是嗎﹖看看你老爸的屁股
- This is insane!
- Yeah? Take a look at your dad's ass,
- 不﹗
- 然后再說我是不是瘋了，嗯﹖
- No!
- Then tell me l'm insane, huh?
- 噢﹗噢﹗
- 嗯﹖嗯﹖看呀﹗
- (all) Oh! Ooh!
- Huh? Huh? Look at it!
看呀﹗嗯﹖嗯﹖
Look at it! Huh? Huh?
- 啊﹗
- 怎么﹖
- Ooh,,,
- What?
噢，太惡心了
(man)) Oh, that's nasty,
我說了我沒生毛囊炎，你這個十足的白痴
l told you l don't have folliculitis,
you blithering idiot,
各位，一定是這藥膏起效了
Well, guys, the ointment
must have worked,
走吧
Let's go,
慢著﹗我給你們看樣東西
Wait! l have something to show ya,
噢﹗
(all) Oh!
(Hans)) What's with this movie
and the ass cheeks?
我的真名叫小杰克.泰勒，萊德是我的綽號
My real name is Jack Taylor,,, Jr,
Red is my nickname,
現在你們知道為什么了，我就是TJ來此的原因
Now you know why,
l'm the whole reason that TJ's here,
該死的，萊德，你在我的房子里做毒品買賣﹗
Goddamn it, Red, You've been
dealing drugs out of my house!
不，爸爸，我發誓，我給這家伙的是一包面粉
No, Dad, l swear,
l gave this guy a bag of flour,
我把一公斤真的毒品倒進馬桶了
l dumped a kilo of the real stuff
down the toilet,
我再也不賣毒品了
l'm finished dealing for good,
木制墊子的那個萊檬綠色的馬桶﹖
The lime green toilet
with the wooden seat?
沒錯，怎么了
- Yeah, why?
- (squawking))
噢﹗
(all) Ooh!
哇﹗
(all) Whoa!
等等，他在飛﹗
Wait a second, He's flying,
他在飛﹗
He's flying,
(squawking))
哇﹗
(all) Whoa!
- (OJ squeals))
- (car horn))
- (tires screeching))
- (crash))
我不想再看到他，立刻﹗
麗莎，我們走
Get him out of my sight, Now,
Lisa, let's go,
就是他，搶了我的耳朵﹗
伊万德.霍利菲爾德的耳朵
That's the one, He got my ear!
Evander Holyfield's ear,
你有權保持沉默，你所說的一切將...
You have to right to remain silent,
Anything you say can and,,,
麗莎，等等﹗
Lisa, wait!
老天，是霍利菲爾德的耳朵
(Arthur) That's Holyfield's ear
for God's sake,
(thunder rolling))
OJ﹖
- (squawking))
- OJ?
OJ，到我這里來，小寶貝你怎么樣﹖
OJ! Come to Daddy,
How's my little boy?
(squawking))
- 你要跟他走﹖
- 我有別的選擇嗎﹖他需要我
- You're going with him?
- What choice do l have? He needs me,
你真的同情他﹖
Are you actually feeling sorry for him?
他在操縱你，你居然能接受這种事
He's manipulating you
and you are buying it,
好吧，行，隨便你怎么做好了，
不過我要把湯姆保釋出來
All right, fine, You do what you gotta do,
l am gonna bail Tom out of jail,
錢呢﹖用你賣毒品的錢﹖
With what? Your drug money?
不，不，不，這是我從老爸的保險箱里偷的
No, no, no, l stole
this out of Dad's safe,
听著，重要的是，必須有人幫助湯姆
Look, the important thing is,
somebody has gotta help Tom,
你知道昨晚發生的事沒有一件是他的錯
You know that nothing that happened
here last night was any of his fault,
真搞笑，這個全世界最友善的家伙卻是
唯一有勇气...
lt's funny, The nicest guy in the world's
the only one with enough balls
...反抗我們老爸的人
to stand up to Dad,
他唯一想要的就是和你共度一段時光
All he wanted to do was
to spend some time with you,
結果給他帶來了什么﹖
Look what it gets him,
真是個模范老爸，我被禁止進入這房子，
而你被禁止离開這房子
Classic Dad, l'm not allowed in the
house, you're not allowed out of it,
他不關心我們，他只關心那只蠢鳥
He doesn't care about us,
Only that stupid bird,
- 嘿，萊德，我能告訴你一件事嗎﹖
- 當然可以
- Hey, Red, can l tell you something?
- Sure,
我知道這听上去很怪异，
但是從我還是個小孩子開始...
l know this is gonna sound weird,
but ever since l was a little kid,,,
...我就一直希望自己變成那只蠢鳥
l used to always wish
that l was that stupid bird,
啊
Aw,
(squawks))
听著，我覺得該是你跟老爸談談的時候了
Look, l think it's about time
you talk to Dad,
至少告訴他你的感受，你能做到的
At least tell him how you feel,
You can do it,
(grunts))
(yells))
你還不明白嗎﹖我們沒道理要畏懼他﹖
Don't you see, we have no reason
to be afraid of him?
啊﹗
- Aah!
- (screaming))
啊﹗
Aah!
(grunting)) Aah!
- (yells))
- (thud)
- 爸爸﹗
- 麗莎，別讓他這樣對你
- Daddy!
- Lisa, don't let him do this to you,
麗莎﹗啊﹗
Lisa! Aah!
- 麗莎﹗
- 湯姆﹗
- Lisa!
- Tom!
萊德把我保釋出來了，他告訴我你在這，
我不會讓你走的
Red bailed me out,,, and told me you
were here and l'm not letting you go,
- 但我...
- 不，你讓我說完
- Yeah, but l'm,,,
- No, You're gonna let me finish,
昨晚是一場惡夢，都是我自己造成的，
因為是我讓他們那樣對我的
l went through hell last night and it was
my fault 'cause l let people do it to me,
現在你在犯同樣的錯誤
And now you're gonna
make the same mistake,
- 但是...
- 這不是你想要的
- Yeah, but,,,
- This isn't what you want,
這是你爸爸想要的，還有，你知道嗎﹖
This is what your father wants,
And you know what?
也許你和我永遠不會在一起，
這讓我很傷心
Maybe you and l,,, never
are gonna work, And that hurts,
但是看著你被一個無情的暴君控制著，
這讓我更傷心
But not as much as watching you
be controlled by a ruthless tyrant
如果他以為這樣會有助于他的成功，讓他見鬼去吧
that would screw his own mother
if he thought it'd help him get ahead,,,
湯姆﹗我沒說要走
Tom! l'm not going,
她...她不走
She's-she's not going,
這點對你而言就這么難以理解，斯坦菲爾德﹖
ls this whole concept too complicated
for you, Stansfield?
不會，不會
No, No,
好啊
All right, (chuckles))
什么...我...是什么讓你留下來的﹖
Wha,,, l,,, What made you stay?
這個
That,
- 你們是怎么...
- 我們終于進行了一次早就該進行的促膝長談
- How did you guys,,,
- We finally had our long overdue talk,
那...那誰接替你在泰國的職位﹖
Then-then who's taking
your place in Thailand?
他
- He is,
- (gong))
- 這是什么﹖
- 啊﹗
- What's this?
- (neck cracks)) Ow!
- 我和你鬧著玩的
- 我不想去，我害怕
- l'm kidding,
- l don't wanna go, l'm afraid,
胡說，每個人都知道...
Nonsense, Everyone knows that, uh,,,
...亞洲人很害怕...
Asian people are very
intimidated by, uh,,,
- 高個子﹖
- 加拿大人﹖
- Tall men?
- Canadians?
- 共和党人﹖
- 黑人﹖
- Republicans?
- Blacks?
- 漢德森﹖
- 是，先生
- Henderson?
- Yes, sir,
我不允許公司里有這种思想
l won't have that kind of thinking
in this company,
這里沒有种族主義生存的空間，你被解雇了
There's no room for racism here,
You're fired,
好了，湯姆，我要說的重點是，
由于公司里有一大部分人要去泰國
Now, Tom, the point that l'm getting to
is that with a big part of the team away,
所以我要讓你接管創意部
l'm gonna want you to take over
the Creative Department,
- 我﹖
- 不用謙讓
- Me?
- No need to be modest,
我看了你留在臥室里的那些构思
l saw those ideas you left
in the living room,
你關于肯尼迪刺殺案的推論，很有道理，
還有關于登月是一個騙局的推論﹖
Your theory on the JFK thing, brilliant,
And the moon landing, a hoax?
你真是有不少重大發現啊
You're really on to something there,
這正是銷售書籍的人該有的思維方式
That's the kind of thinking
that's gonna sell books,
謝謝，先生
Uh, thank you, sir,
再見，爸爸，一路平安
Bye, Daddy, Have a safe flight,
爸爸，妙极了，你提拔了湯姆
Well, Dad,,, that's fantastic,
You promoted Tom,
是的，我認為有膽子在我的波斯地毯上撒尿的人...
Yeah, well, l figure anyone who's got
the guts to piss on my Persian carpet
...一定具備了成功的必要條件。
斯坦菲爾德﹗
has gotta have what it takes,
Stansfield!
(trickling))
- 你到底在干什么﹖
- 我在設法要回我的工作，先生
- What the hell are you doing?
- Just trying to get my job back, sir,
(. ''If I Had $ 1 000000''
by Barenaked Ladies))
- (Lisa squeals))
- (chuckles))
在發生所有這些事之后，在經歷了這一切之后
(Tom)) You know, after everything
that happened, after all I went through,
我想那天真是我的幸運日。
而且我不是唯一一個幸運的人
I guess it was my lucky day.
And I'm not the only one.
按照麗莎和萊德的提議
Based on Lisa and Red's suggestions,
杰克從上到下改組了公司
Jack restructured the company
from top to bottom.
甚至把禮拜五穿便服的制度改成了
每天都可以穿便服
Even instituting casual
Fridays every day.
上禮拜五是漢德森連續第27天工作...
And last Friday was Henderson's
...期間沒有被解雇過
without being fired.
OJ戒掉了毒癮，現在他只喝啤酒了
OJ's back off the drugs
and now he only drinks beer.
(burps))
不過他偶爾還是會想起過去的事情
(chuckles)) But he still has
an occasional flashback.
(squawks))
杰克懇求奧德莉回來上班，
不過她已經找到工作了
Jack begged Audrey to come back,
but she got a job
居然是在咖啡館上班
at, of all places, a coffee shop.
- 噢﹗
- Ew!
- Ugh!
- 噢﹗
- Ew!
太難喝了
This is terrible!
漢斯已經成功開始運轉公司設在泰國的工厂
Hans succeeded in turning around
the company's factory in Thailand.
不過顯然他仍然在努力地适應當地習俗
But apparently he's still struggling
to cope with the local customs.
- 坐到后面去﹗
- 什么﹖
- Back of bus!
- Excuse me?
- 你們這种人要坐在后面
- 你侮辱我﹗
- You people belong back of bus,
- That's an outrage!
老兄，我不會讓你這樣對待我，就因為我...
Man, l'm not gonna let you treat me
like that merely because l'm,,,
吸煙﹗要吸煙就坐到后面去﹗
Smoking! Smokers belong back of bus!
(coughing))
至于我，升職之后
As for me, with my new promotion,
終于有机會將我自己的經歷寫成書
I could at last write books
based on my own experiences.
- 于是我寫了
- 謝謝
- So I did.
- Thank you,
麗莎也終于能夠從事她自己喜歡的職業
And Lisa was finally able to pursue
a career that she loved.
有句老話，你們都曾听人說過﹕
You know, you ever heard
someone say that old expression.:
“為什么坏事總發生在我身上﹖”
''Why does everything bad
always happen to me?''
我無法認同他們，因為我已經知曉，
只要他們肯停下腳步...
Well, I don't get those people...
'cause I've learned that if they just stop
...查看一下，他們就會認識到，凡事皆有因
and look around, they'd realize
that everything happens for a reason.
(. ''If I Had $ 1 000000''
by Barenaked Ladies continues))
[謝謝觀賞]
---NewMov字幕翻譯小組制作---
翻譯&校對﹕bigliar
(. ''Burn the Boats'' by Early Edison))
我早就說了他遲早會見到老板的屁股
(TJ)) I told him he'd see
the ass sooner or later.